<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Maciek's blog</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Korona Gór Polskich: 1 - Łysica</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/korona-g%C3%B3r-polskich_-1-%C5%82ysica/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/korona-g%C3%B3r-polskich_-1-%C5%82ysica/</guid><description>Fajnie jest robić rzeczy razem. Ja lubię chodzić po górach, Taida zdobywać odznaki, zapisaliśmy się więc do Klubu Zdobywców Korony Gór Polski, wyrobiliśmy książeczki i zrobiliśmy spreadsheet ze szczytami do zdobycia. Na tym się na jakiś czas skończyło.
Ostatnio zbliżające się narodziny Kaczki uświadomiły nam, że wkrótce realizacja tej ambicji spadnie na daleki plan, warto więc ruszyć tyłki póki się da. Łysica to oczywisty wybór: można obrócić z Warszawy w jeden dzień, wejście jest proste, powinno dać radę i w 7 miesiącu ciąży.</description></item><item><title>Granie Turbacza</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/granie-turbacza/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/granie-turbacza/</guid><description>Dojazd PKP, ale z Krakowa jest bus; orientuję się dopiero w pociągu, choć na bilecie jest na czerwono: bus zastępczy. Trochę korków, w stronę Krakowa pierwsze trzy kilometry to 40 minut, ale mimo tego daję radę, zdążamy na nasz pociąg. Otwarte wagony są lepsze niż przedziały. W przedziale nie da się rozprostować nóg, i jest problem jak współpasażer brzydko pachnie albo głośno słucha muzyki na słuchawkach.
Na stacji w Nowym Targu wpadamy w łapy taksówkarza, już nas nie opuści do końca wyjazdu.</description></item><item><title>Pārśvakoṇāsana w Harszu</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/p%C4%81r%C5%9Bvako%E1%B9%87%C4%81sana-w-harszu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/p%C4%81r%C5%9Bvako%E1%B9%87%C4%81sana-w-harszu/</guid><description>Najpierw dowiedzieliśmy się, że joga to oddychanie. Nic więcej. Wdech i wydech. Wdech i wydech.
Potem, że joga to rozluźnianie. Nie rozciąganie, Żeby dobrze oddychać trzeba być luźnym, mieć dostęp do brzucha. Jesteśmy spięci, siedzenie przy biurku nas spina, sport nas spina, współczesne życie jest szkodliwe. Trzeba się rozluźnić. Trzeba też dobrze ustawić miednicę. Wtedy oddech jest swobodny, z brzucha.
Ważne jest, żeby jelito grube, nasz drugi mózg, było czyste. Wtedy propriocepcja działa, czujemy co się w nas dzieje, i lepiej też czujemy, co się dzieje w innych.</description></item><item><title>Nad Zielonym</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/nad-zielonym/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/nad-zielonym/</guid><description>Czy jestem na wsi, czy w mieście, żyję w izolacji, w bańce. Na polu biwakowym tak się nie da, jest się blisko ludzi — może nie do końca przypadkowych, bo już ci, którzy decydują się spędzać czas w namiotach, to wyselekcjonowana grupa — lecz wciąż nie tak sprofilowana jak moje codzienne otoczenie.
Okazuje się, że nie ma się czego bać. Groźnie wyglądający brodacz w kamuflarzu i łysy w czarnym t-shircie przynoszą nam świeżo zrąbany pień na ognisko.</description></item><item><title>Czterech facetów w dwóch łódkach</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/czterech-facet%C3%B3w-w-dw%C3%B3ch-%C5%82%C3%B3dkach/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/czterech-facet%C3%B3w-w-dw%C3%B3ch-%C5%82%C3%B3dkach/</guid><description>Spływ pontonowy Bugiem z Tuchlina do Młynarzy odbył się po raz drugi, można więc uznać, że to już impreza cykliczna. Liczba uczestników oraz jednostek pływających wzrosła o sto procent. Poza pontonem &amp;ldquo;dla dwóch zakochanych wędkarzy&amp;rdquo; zwodowaliśmy też trzyosobowego Jastrzębia Morskiego. Załogę mniejszej jednostki stanowili Kozło i Jordan, zaś do większej wsiadł Marek wraz z niżej podpisanym, przy czym miejsce trzeciej osoby zajęła sterta bagaży — wyposażeni byliśmy też znacznie lepiej niż przed rokiem.</description></item><item><title>GSB, Bartne-Komańcza</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gsb-bartne-koma%C5%84cza/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gsb-bartne-koma%C5%84cza/</guid><description>Start Odkąd zapanował dobrobyt i wolny rynek, w góry dojechać się da tylko własnym samochodem. W zeszłym roku do Świeradowa-Zdroju dotarliśmy z Jeleniej Góry taksówką. Tym razem możliwości dojazdu do Małastowa wydają się jeszcze bardziej ograniczone. Z ratunkiem spieszy mama, oferując, że nas zawiezie samochodem. Podróż na Przełęcz Małastowską mija szybko i przyjemnie, na miejsce docieramy wczesnym popołudniem, potem jeszcze 20 minut spaceru pod górę i jesteśmy w schronisku PTTK.</description></item><item><title>Gran Bis</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gran-bis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gran-bis/</guid><description>Spaleni słońcem Wydawało się, że spacer będzie lajtowy, 10 km, głównie z górki. Nie wziąłem pod uwagę uruchamiającej agorafobię ekspozycji, odwodnienia i niewystraczającej ochrony przed słońcem – ramiona spalone, brak picia na szczęście bez większych konsekwencji. Będę musiał bardziej na serio podchodzić do roli przewodnika, pilnować smarowania i naciskać na sikanie w krzakach. Za to dzięki budzącym lęk ekspozycjom wiem już, która przyjaciółka odziedziczy którą paletę. Mi zostaną koty.
Gospodarze Daniel i Marcin są jedną nogą wyprowadzeni na stałe na Kanary.</description></item><item><title>Krzyżne</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/krzy%C5%BCne/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/krzy%C5%BCne/</guid><description>W Bukowinie Tatrzańskiej, na stokach Wierchu Olczańskiego, stawiałem swoje pierwsze kroki na nartach, pierwszy raz skręciłem z pługa, pierwszy raz spadłem z orczyka i chyba też pierwszy raz poczułem, jaką frajdę może dawać zasuwanie z górki na dwóch deskach, przy zachowaniu elementarnej kontroli. To było grubo ponad 30 lat temu. Od tego czasu jeździłem do większych ośrodków, przywyczaiłem się do dziesiątków kilometrów tras, których zwiedzenie zajmuje wiele dni, wychodzenia z kwatery na nartach i tak też wracania do niej.</description></item><item><title>Granica</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/granica/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/granica/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Seafood Paella from Memory</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/seafood-paella-from-memory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/seafood-paella-from-memory/</guid><description>Once something is out on the internet, it’s there forever. Of course, the websites come and go, entire provinces disappear, but the information stays there in some form, in search engine caches, in the Wayback Machine, often copied across multiple sites. Or so I hoped recently, while looking for a paella recipe, which I originally found around ten years ago and then used, with some success, through the years. No luck.</description></item><item><title>Dwóch facetów w łódce</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dw%C3%B3ch-facet%C3%B3w-w-%C5%82%C3%B3dce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dw%C3%B3ch-facet%C3%B3w-w-%C5%82%C3%B3dce/</guid><description>Wrzesień to trochę późno na tego rodzaju eskapady. Pogoda niepewna, może być chłodno. Dopisało nam szczęście, weekend jest ciepły i suchy, wodujemy więc ponton przy ujściu Tuchełki i rozpoczynamy przygodę.
Przed Brańszczykiem Bug wije się wśród łąk. Wysokie skarpy zamieszkały jaskółki, rzeka gdzieniegdzie zabiera grunt spod porastających wybrzeża sosen, te walą się do wody i trzeba je omijać. Powoli zapada zmierzch, nad nami pojawiają się nietoperze, a na brzegach wędkarze i korzystający z pogodnego weekendu piknikowicze.</description></item><item><title>GSS, etap I</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gss-etap-i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/gss-etap-i/</guid><description>Droga Jest szeroko, wygodnie, choć bywa stromo pod górę. Najpierw szosa, potem szutrówka grzbietami gór, czasem chodnik z finezyjnie ułożonych kamieni, to znów trylinka inkrustowana granitem z okolicznych gór. Tak jest przez Góry Izerskie i Karkonosze. Później, w Rudawach Śląskich, Górach Kruczych i Kamiennych, też jest droga, ale czasem szlak się gubi, odchodzi mało znaczącą dróżką przez łąkę, przerwany jest wiatrołomem. Znaki znikają na kilkaset metrów. Zagadujemy się – na temat Houellebecqua, muzyki, płci mózgu, związków… my idzemy tam, szlak gdzie indziej.</description></item><item><title>Creating slide decks in Jupyter notebook</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/creating-slide-decks-in-jupyter-notebook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/creating-slide-decks-in-jupyter-notebook/</guid><description>My job involves organising and analysing data, and training and evaluating machine learning models. In addition, the customers like to see demonstrations or progress updates for their models, so every now and then I also have to put together a slide deck. For better or worse, I use Jupyter notebooks as the main tool for the data management part, so I thought it would be convenient to prepare my slides in the same environment.</description></item><item><title>Flooded Queensland Penne</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</guid><description>January 2011 found us in eastern Australia, desperately trying to get to from Cairns to Sydney in time for our flight back home. Despite having a few weeks at our disposal, us reaching Sydney on time was far from certain, due to epic floods that affected much of coastal Queensland. So, we drove around trying to find a passable way South, coming across what looked like deserted towns, with empty shelves at grocery stores and rationed bread, as supplies could not be delivered due to flooded roads.</description></item><item><title>One Pound Soup</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/one-pound-soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/one-pound-soup/</guid><description>I took my first steps towards independent, adult living one summer in the middle of my university course. I stayed for two months in a shared apartment in central London. It was a summer internship, well paid, but not being used to a regular income, freaked out by the prices of everything in London being a few times higher than in Warsaw, I tried to live on a very tight budget of £50 a week – that included food and tube tickets.</description></item><item><title>Jamie's Fish</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/jamies-fish/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/jamies-fish/</guid><description>There are recipes that I gleaned from the Internet, and which I am very fond of. It would be presumptious and unfair to the fine people who first published them online to plagiarise their efforts on this humble blog. But then, if I had prepared a certain dish dozens of times, if I made custom adjustments and modifications, if the sequence of activities is so ingrained in my synapses that preparing it is like driving a car or putting my shoes on – then perhaps it is fair game, after all?</description></item><item><title>KDD 2018: The Rest</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-the-rest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-the-rest/</guid><description>KDD 2018 was intense. Workshops and keynotes started at 8 AM and the poster sessions were runing until 9 PM. There was a dozen tracks running in parallel, so choosing the session to attend was hard – there was always something else potentially interesting going on at the same time. For the first two days I tried to pay close attention and write up comprehensible notes from the tutorials and workshops, but that was not sustainable, so from the third day on I sat back, relaxed, listened more, wrote less.</description></item><item><title>KDD 2018: Quantum Machine Learning</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-quantum-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-quantum-machine-learning/</guid><description>It must be an exciting time for quantum computing researches. Up until a few years ago all work in this domain was about building theoretical models of what will be possible once we have a quantum computer. Today, a number of companies have built and made available physical quantum computers. So far those are toy-size, proofs of concept, with no practical application, but this gives hope that practical devices will become available in a few years’ time, so wider community should take notice.</description></item><item><title>KDD 2018: Common Model Infrastructure</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-common-model-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-common-model-infrastructure/</guid><description>Go away and have fun building models like there is no tomorrow. After all, we do the real creative work, innovation, science. The software and operations engineers just deal with the plumbing and have an easy, predictable job compared to us, data scientists. This might not be a mindset many would admit to, but subconciously we do tend to underestimate the importance of others’ jobs. To be fair, the enginneering and operations folks are not much better in this respect – everyone tends to think their work is more demanding and output more valuable than average.</description></item><item><title>KDD 2018: Explainable Models for Healthcare AI</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-explainable-models-for-healthcare-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-explainable-models-for-healthcare-ai/</guid><description>The Explainable Models for Healthcare AI tutorial was presented by a trio from KenSci Inc. that included a data scientist and a clinician. The premise of the session was that explainability is particularly important in healthcare applications of machine learning, due to the far-reaching consequences of decisions, high cost of mistakes, fairness and compliance requirements. The tutorial walked through a number of aspects of interpretability and discussed techniques that can be applied to explain model predictions.</description></item><item><title>KDD 2018: Deep Learning for Computational Health</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-deep-learning-for-computational-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/kdd-2018-deep-learning-for-computational-health/</guid><description>The Deep Learnig for Computational Health tutorial was presented by Jimeng Sun, Edward Choi and Cao Xiao. With the electronic health record (EHR) data comprising free text, structured codes, time series and images, a wide range of deep learning techniques has been successfully applied to their analysis. The presenters focussed on capturing the information about the sequence of patient’s visits, interpretability of models and representation learning for textual and structured data.</description></item><item><title>Precision confidence interval in the presence of unreliable labels</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/precision-confidence-interval-in-the-presence-of-unreliable-labels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/precision-confidence-interval-in-the-presence-of-unreliable-labels/</guid><description>Consider a binary classifier that produced the following counts of true positives (TP) and false positives (FP) on test data.
tp_observed = 5285 fp_observed = 3184 We would like to know the 95% confidence interval for precision metric of this classifier. Goutte and Gaussier showed that precision follows the Beta distribution with the counts of TPs and FPs as parameters, adjusted for prior. We will use uniform prior, $Beta(1,1)$.
import pymc3 as pm with pm.</description></item><item><title>Pink Soup</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</guid><description>From my childhood I remember that to maintain the staple lunch of a soup and a main course through the summer heatwaves, the soup had to be replaced with a cold, often milk-based concoction. It is a peculiarly eastern European thing. From Balkans to the Baltic, from tarator to cold borscht, you will find a multitude of summer recipes for a cold soup. Somehow, the westerners often find the idea repulsive.</description></item><item><title>RAPIDS 2018</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/rapids-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/rapids-2018/</guid><description>Having for the last year incessantly worried about the day when someone asks how we achieved a certain model metric, and not being able to answer or even replicate the result, I found the subject of Reproducibility and Provenance in Data Science mini-conference – RAPIDS in short – much to my interest. The solutions to the provenance tracking and reproducibility problem I came up with so far were hand-cranked and built on top of tools whose selection was influenced more by my personal preferences than the prevailing industry practices.</description></item><item><title>Kuzyni Any Rity</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/kuzyni-any-rity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/kuzyni-any-rity/</guid><description>Alentejo Mam do krajów śródziemnomorskich sentyment. Kombinacja klimatu, jedzenia, kultury, architektury, usposobienia, a pewnie w głównej mierze jakieś abstrakcyjne, atrakcyjne pojęcie “śródziemnomorskości”, ciągną mnie w ten rejon. Do Portugalii zawsze jednak przyjeżdżam pod jakimś pretekstem. Poprzednio było to rodzinne spotkanie w okolicach Porto, teraz odwiedziny u pary przyjaciół, Any Rity i Davida, mieszkających w Castro Verde, niewielkim miasteczku w regionie Alentejo, dwie godziny jazdy na południe od Lizbony. To dobra baza do wycieczek nad morze, zarówno na zachodnie (Alentejo) jak i południowe wybrzeże (Algarve).</description></item><item><title>Franklin, tygodnie 7-9</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/franklin-tygodnie-7-9/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/franklin-tygodnie-7-9/</guid><description>Konie, joga i Trump The Log House się prawie nie zmienił, woda wciąż wali siarą, zasięgu komórki wciąż nie ma, nadal jest to miejsce, które uwielbiam. Trochę go owady zżerają, i więcej gości – podobno czerwiec to sezon. Najpierw pojawiają się Christie i Larry, który jak nie wie co powiedzieć, to mówi “rock’n’roll”. Przywieźli na weekend osiem koni – na jednym się przejechałem, było fajnie. Przez dwa tygodnie pod dwójką urzęduje Kenneth, sprzedawca materacy, któreg prawie nie widuję, bo pracuje siedem dni w tygodniu, wstaje po tym jak wyjdę, a wraca jak już leżę w łóżku.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning in Three Pages</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/machine-learning-in-three-pages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/machine-learning-in-three-pages/</guid><description>A supervised machine learning problem can be viewed as approximating an unknown target function $f:\mathcal{X}\rightarrow \mathcal{Y}$ by constructing a function $\hat{f}:\mathcal{X}\rightarrow \mathcal{Y}$ using a set of $k$ training examples $T=\{\left&amp;lt;X_i, Y_i\right&amp;gt; | i=1..k, X_i\in\mathcal{X}, Y_i=f(X_i)\}$. The function $\hat{f}$ is referred to as a model. The goal of machine learning is to construct the model in such a way that its results on $X\in\mathcal{X}\setminus T$ are close – according to some measure – to $f(X)$.</description></item><item><title>Arabba Fennel salad, cold or hot</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</guid><description>A skiing week in a rented apartment usually means serious culinary constraints. So, we have picked the location that is close to the slopes, so that we do not have to take a bus, or walk for 20 minutes in ski boots, and that is not going to break the bank – but other considerations, such as well-equipped kitchen or proximity to the shops inevitably were of secondary importance. We could eat in the resturant, sure, but if we could afford the extortionate prices the resort eateries charge, then presumably we could have stayed in a proper hotel instead of a holiday apartment?</description></item><item><title>What do you do with celeriac</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</guid><description>Having decided to live apart from civilisation, on the outskirts of a tiny hamlet, two hundred thousand souls, I am at the mercy of my local Tesco as far as food supplies are concerned. Some years ago they decided to stop carrying avocados for a few months. Imagine that! You city folks do not understand what real hardship is. Now there is no celeriac. Last autumn celeriac was in constant supply, but somehow it has fallen out of favour this year.</description></item><item><title>A Software Developer's Take on Zeppelin Notebooks</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/a-software-developers-take-on-zeppelin-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/a-software-developers-take-on-zeppelin-notebooks/</guid><description>For the past two months I have used Zeppelin-based notebooks as my primary IDE for data exploration, experiment documentation and prototyping of production code. While the former two notebook use cases are perfectly legitimate, I would argue that Zeppelin is poorly suited for production code prototyping. This is primarily due to high barrier to extraction of common code to libraries. In Jupyter, for example, all it takes to extract a function to a shareable module is to copy it from the notebook to a Python file stored in the same directory as the notebook.</description></item><item><title>Na południe od Nashville</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/na-po%C5%82udnie-od-nashville/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/na-po%C5%82udnie-od-nashville/</guid><description>Prius Są pewnie miejsca w USA – Nowy Jork, na przykład – gdzie można przylecieć, nie mieć samochodu i nic na tym nie stracić. Tennessee nie jest takim miejscem. Kiedyś już się o tym przekonałem, pedałując dwadzieścia kilometrów do najbliższego sklepu po mleko. Powtórnie mi o tym przypomniały trzy tygodnie kiszenia się w biznesowym hotelu między Interstate 65, rozległymi parkingami i nielicznymi biurowcami. Tym razem wynająłem więc samochód. Najtańsza opcja to Ford Mustang, ale już z takich zabawek wyrosłem.</description></item><item><title>Digital Hygiene Part 3: Alternative to Google</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-3-alternative-to-google/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-3-alternative-to-google/</guid><description>I vaguely remember Internet search before Google. There was AltaVista and perhaps some other contenders, like Inktomi, Lycos or Excite. Google blew them all out of the water in early 2000s, thanks to minimalistic, user-friendly and search-focused home page and relevant results, not polluted by “sponsored entries”. Over the next decade this evolved into effective monopoly of Internet search, efforts from heavyweight competitors (Microsoft Bing) notwithstanding. Meanwhile, Google spread into multitude of other services whose competitive edge relied on vast amount of knowledge about our habits, interests and values, accumulated as a result of us using those services and giving the data away in return.</description></item><item><title>Digital Hygiene Part 2: Password Manager</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-2-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-2-password-manager/</guid><description>In this installment we are going to look at the elephant in the room of digital security: passwords. Two most common sins against security committed by millions, or billions of Internet users are 1) weak passwords and 2) password reuse. It is now widely recognised that it is not the users who are to blame, but the password system itself. It is inconceivable that a single person can remember dozens of different, complicated passwords for different online services the modern world all but forces us to use.</description></item><item><title>Digital Hygiene Part 1: VPN</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-1-vpn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-1-vpn/</guid><description>A few years ago I used to not care much about the digital trail I left all over the internet. The optimistic assumption “nothing to hide, nothing to fear”, convenience of numerous new services that offered some minor perk in exchange for my data, and the general trend for the population of developed world to share more and more, all pushed in that direction. Since then, a couple of developments changed my attitude.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Lambda Calculus</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/introduction-to-lambda-calculus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/introduction-to-lambda-calculus/</guid><description>Software is pervasive in the modern world and has influence over many aspects of our lives. In some cases, such as avionics or medical equipment control, human life depends on the correctness of software. Yet, high profile cases of bugs do not inspire confidence in the state of software engineering.
The “software crisis” is a phenomenon recognised by practitioners of the field. Several ways of addressing the reliability issue have been proposed: from reliance on programmer’s discipline, through tools that perform post-hoc validation of programs to ensure they do not contain suspicious coding patterns, to languages that restrict valid programs to ones whose properties can be formally proven.</description></item><item><title>Elegy to the Bliss</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/elegy-to-the-bliss/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/elegy-to-the-bliss/</guid><description>I met Katja at Barleylands Farmers Market near Billericay. She was selling various smoked goods, of which some – sea salt, garlic, cheese – looked weird, but whole trout caught my attention. Katja told me it can be eaten cold or heated up and served with potatoes, the latter of which I found a bit surprising. In the end I tried it cold, on a sandwich with home-made sourdough rye bread, and it was glorious.</description></item><item><title>Zen i sztuka kąpieli</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/zen-i-sztuka-k%C4%85pieli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/zen-i-sztuka-k%C4%85pieli/</guid><description>Rakieta Dziwolągi, egzotyka, ciekawostki – to absorbuje gawiedź. Stąd obraz Japonii, w który wyposaża nas popkultura, to dziwne rytuały, obca zupełnie mentalność, ekstrawaganckie stroje, high-tech, kodeks honorowy. Na górze Tsukuba tej inności nie widać, ludzie wchodzą jak w Europie, pocą się i dyszą jak w Europie, mówią “dzień dobry” jak w Europie. Ubierają się trochę może inaczej: więcej jest wynalazków, elementów garderoby które dobitnie podkreślają “teraz jestem na wycieczce górskiej”, te wszystkie techniczne leginsy i skarpety pod specjalnymi szortami, kapelusze i czapki od słońca, butle, plecaki i plecaczki, saszetki, kije.</description></item><item><title>Datapalooza, or IBM's Land Grab</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/datapalooza-or-ibms-land-grab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/datapalooza-or-ibms-land-grab/</guid><description>IBM Watson’s spectacular success in Jeopardy a couple years ago was widely reported and highlighted the fact that the company, not generally considered to be at the forefront of technological innovation for the past 15 years or so, is attempting to carve for itself a large slice of the big data/data science/machine learning/cognitive computing/whatever term is fashionable this week pie. I did not appreciate the scope of their foray into this space until the Datapalooza Mashup event today.</description></item><item><title>Auguststraße i bunkier</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/auguststra%C3%9Fe-i-bunkier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/auguststra%C3%9Fe-i-bunkier/</guid><description>Z jednej strony ulicę zamyka Tacheles. Artyści się wyprowadzili, były squat stoi pusty. Z podcieni na piętrze wciąż straszą rzeźby ze złomu, maszkarony z nosami zrobionymi z kranów. Z bocznej ściany wydostać się próbuje gigantyczny karaluch. Na drugim końcu jest cmentarz garnizonowy. Po przeciwnej stronie ulicy, na zrujnowanej kamienicy, napis “Soldaten sind Mörder”, oraz transparent głoszący, że zatroskanym mieszczanom oraz ich nazistowskim poplecznikom należy wyrwać zęby.
Pod numerami 11-13 mieści sie była Jüdische Mädchenschule – budynek prosty i funkcjonalny, zbudowany przez Aleksandra Beera w latach 20 XX w.</description></item><item><title>Hello Katie</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/hello-katie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/hello-katie/</guid><description>Wyjechaliśmy znów na Wielkanoc do parku narodowego. Poprzednio, wiele już lat temu, wybraliśmy się do Peak District. Mieszkaliśmy na campingu w naszym maleńkim namiocie. Ania przed wyjazdem zrobiła mazurki, podzieliliśmy się nimi z obozującymi obok wspinaczami z Machesteru. W zamian uraczeni zostaliśmy winem z kartonu oraz piosenkami z mp3 na temat zwyczajów mieszkańców Yorkshire. Bardzo był to fajny wyjazd, zrobiliśmy wtedy długi trek wzdłuż Stanage Edge, wyszliśmy wcześnie rano, wróciliśmy po zmroku, bardzo zmęczeni.</description></item><item><title>Ketosis No. 2</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</guid><description>Have you heard of ketosis? No? Apparently it’s the best thing since the sliced bread, only even better, because there is no bread, so no need to slice anything. There is no bread, because ketosis is all about getting your energy from fat. Apparently a chap has done it for a year, lost weight, has better cholesterol and some other metrics, feels great. Right, count me in. But, the scientific way to do it is being very exact with amounts of all the food ingredients, and really struggling to find foodstuffs which are fatty enough.</description></item><item><title>Osiem dni na szczycie Afryki</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/osiem-dni-na-szczycie-afryki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/osiem-dni-na-szczycie-afryki/</guid><description>Team Kilimanjaro ma dość skomplikowaną strukturę: płaci się firmie Lewin Ventures Limited zarejestrowanej na Gibraltarze, zaś pieniądze wpłynąć mają na konto banku w Rydze. Adresy kontaktowe są w Londynie. Pomimo tego organizacyjnie wszystko okazało się dopięte na ostatni guzik, z jednym tylko drobnym potknięciem: nasze formularze z zamówieniem sprzętu do wypożyczenia nie dotarły do przewodnika, tak, że trzeba je było odtwarzać z pamięci. Ania i ja pożyczaliśmy tylko śpiwory i jedną parę getrów, Magda natomiast miała długą listę, zawierającą też kurtkę, latarkę i rękawice.</description></item><item><title>Build or Buy</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/build-or-buy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/build-or-buy/</guid><description>As programmers, whenever we embark on writing a piece of code, we risk being accused of reinventing the wheel and succumbing to Not Invented Here syndrome. There are nowadays dozens of libraries, framework and other software products of some description for every task imaginable. Yet, the answer to buy vs. build is not as clear-cut as might appear at a glance. The Programmer’s Paradox blog post which made rounds in programming circles in November points out that effective use of third-party software requires deep understanding of its inner workings.</description></item><item><title>A Pitfall of Global Execution Context</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/a-pitfall-of-global-execution-context/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/a-pitfall-of-global-execution-context/</guid><description>The convenience of Scala’s Future concept makes it the default tool for all kinds of programming tasks that call for asynchrony. There seems nothing simpler than wrapping a block of code in future { }, then, when compilation fails, importing scala.concurrent.ExecutionContext.Implicits.global, and we’re done, the code runs asynchronously. We can then use the computed result (if any) in further futures, or if we want to break out of the future world, do Await.</description></item><item><title>Sailor Fodder</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sailor-fodder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sailor-fodder/</guid><description>Picture this: you try to bring a massive pot of water to boil to cook some rice. The meal was supposed to be served 15 minutes ago, and the water still refuses to boil. Suddenly, the floor lurches from underneath your feet, you are violently thrown against the cooker and only a small miracle saves you from third-degree burns. Eventually, you manage to put some rice into the water, and after another half an hour there is some hope it might have softened a little.</description></item><item><title>Nigdy więcej na Bałtyku</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/nigdy-wi%C4%99cej-na-ba%C5%82tyku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/nigdy-wi%C4%99cej-na-ba%C5%82tyku/</guid><description>Żeglowałem po morzu trzy razy, za każdym razem po Bałtyku, we wrześniu, na Warszawskiej Nike. Namówili mnie przyjaciele – żeglarze, czyli Jerzy, Mierniczy oraz Piotr. Najpierw był tydzień Świnoujście – Kopenhaga – Gdynia. Było chłodnawo, ale pogoda niezła, i nie chorowałem (wachty kambuzowe miałem w portach), tak, że nawet mi się podobało. Kolejny raz był krótki wypad Łeba – Bornholm – Gdynia, z niezapomnianym kapitanem Achtelikiem, w wolnym czasie sztygarem z Bytomia.</description></item><item><title>Scala in North Lakes</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-in-north-lakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-in-north-lakes/</guid><description>A Scala conference, far from any significant technology hub? With no call for papers? With hikes planned in what is one of the wettest parts of the country? Without Martin Odersky? What could possibly go wrong? A lot. But, apart from a few of the speakers not making it, nothing did, and Scala World was probably as good as a Scala conference can get.
Instead of summarising individual talks, I will focus on the major themes.</description></item><item><title>Kto chce na Kilimandżaro</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/kto-chce-na-kilimand%C5%BCaro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/kto-chce-na-kilimand%C5%BCaro/</guid><description>W styczniu wchodzimy z Anią na Kilimandżaro i szukamy towarzystwa.
Itinerer 16 stycznia (sobota): Lot do Nairobi (09:00, Heathrow, 8.5h). Nocleg w hotelu gdzieś przy lotnisku. 17: Bus z Nairobi do Arusha (około 5h). Nocleg w Arusha załatwiony przez Team Kilimanjaro (TK). 18-25: Wejście na Kilimandżaro (8 day TK Lemosho ‘Excel Series’, z noclegiem w kraterze). 26-29: Safari: Tarangire, Ngorongoro, Lake Manyara, dzień z buszmenami uczącymi surwiwalu. Organizowane przez Safari Tours Tanzania, opcja semi-luxury.</description></item><item><title>Sans Marigold</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sans-marigold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sans-marigold/</guid><description>I like travelling a lot – that is, I like it a lot to travel, rather than travelling a lot is what I like – getting to know different cultures, cuisines, all that stuff. Those of you who understand Polish, or are willing to suffer automated translation, can read more about my travel exploits on another blog. This year I have been to Greece and Georgia, and if there is anything common between those two escapades, it is that in those lands of highly regarded cuisine I ended up enjoying salads the most.</description></item><item><title>Tam, gdzie mówią w Kartuli</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tam-gdzie-m%C3%B3wi%C4%85-w-kartuli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tam-gdzie-m%C3%B3wi%C4%85-w-kartuli/</guid><description>Jest trochę przed piątą rano. Podchodzimy do lądowania, wokoło zupełna ciemność. Czy w tym kraju nie mają elektryczności?
W kolejce do wymiany dolarów na lari. Tuż obok szklana ściana terminalu. Za szybą taksówkarz z kartką, na której wymienione są wszystkie turystyczne miejscowości między Tbilisi a Batumi. Co chwila puka w szybę, żeby zwrócić uwagę oczekujących w kolejce turystów. Chętnie wszedłby do środka, ale wstępu broni uzbrojony w pistolet maszynowy ochroniarz.</description></item><item><title>Między Ateną a Prorokiem Eliaszem</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/mi%C4%99dzy-aten%C4%85-a-prorokiem-eliaszem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/mi%C4%99dzy-aten%C4%85-a-prorokiem-eliaszem/</guid><description>Αθήνα Hotel Ionihos wystrojem przywołuje na myśl lata siedemdziesiąte: w foyer ściany wyłożone sklejką w tekowym, matowym pomarańczu, prostokątne zestawy kanapowe, spójność stylistyczną zaburza tylko posadzka z prawdziwego kamienia zamiast lastriko. Śniadanie skromne, na smażone jajka trzeba polować, bo szybko znikają, żadnych warzyw ani jogurtu, niedojrzałe kiwi w charakterze źródła witamin. W nocy kaloryfer grzeje, a na zewnątrz 17 stopni. O szóstej rano świergot ptaków, ryk syreny policyjnej i autobusowych silników skutecznie wyrywa ze snu.</description></item><item><title>Haskell Exchange 2014</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-exchange-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-exchange-2014/</guid><description>I was surprised to find that despite all-star line-up of speakers, this year’s Haskell Exchange was not as well attended and lower key than the 2013 edition. We were back to SkillsMatter headquarters, this time round with gym music blasting from the speakers during breaks and with no aircon for added frowziness. The talks were good though, some of them very much so.
Safe, Zero-Cost Coercions in Haskell Simon Peyton-Jones arrived bare-footed and dispelled one of the illusions I have been holding on to for quite a while, that the minimal core language of GHC, System FC, is sound beyond any reasonable doubt.</description></item><item><title>Obrazki z Rumunii</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/obrazki-z-rumunii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/obrazki-z-rumunii/</guid><description>Gaz Cholerne konkurencyjne standardy. W Timișoarze zaopatrzyć sie mieliśmy w prowiant na cztery-pięć dni oraz pojemnik z gazem. Razowy chleb zrobiliśmy w domu i przywieźliśmy ze sobą, na miejscu kupiliśmy suchą kiełbasę, kawałek wędzonki, rybki w puszce, ryż, zupy i sosy w proszku, suszone owoce, orzechy oraz kilo czekolady. Zakupiona w miejscowym sklepie turystycznym butla z gwintowanym przyłączem typu UNEF okazała się (oczywiście) nie pasować do naszego palnika typu Campingaz. W hotelu wyciągnąłem scyzoryk i sukcesywnie przycinając plastikowe ząbki na klemie mocującej palnik do butli zmusiłem w końcu ten zestaw do odpalenia.</description></item><item><title>The Loin of Patience</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-loin-of-patience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-loin-of-patience/</guid><description>When I was younger I could not understand the social imperative to treat people older than oneself – in particular the elderly – with esteem. In what way does having lived through a number of decades entitle one to more respect than is shown to a similarly worthy youth? With time I started to appreciate the worth of experience and accept that there are qualities that come with age. One such quality that is stereotypically associated with the elderly and denied the young is patience.</description></item><item><title>Haskell Exchange 2013</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-exchange-2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-exchange-2013/</guid><description>The second edition of Haskell Exchange has seen over 70 enthusiasts – primarily from London area, but Hungarian and German contingents were noticeable as well – gathered in a crypt of a church in Clerkenwell. The schedule was intense, so unlike with the events I related in the past I won’t attempt to describe all of the talks in detail, but will just focus on the ones which I found particularly intriguing – i.</description></item><item><title>Scala Futures on a Single Thread</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-futures-on-a-single-thread/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-futures-on-a-single-thread/</guid><description>Futures, introduced into Scala standard library in version 2.10, quickly became one of the cornerstones of Scala concurrency. Their main selling point is the ease of composition. A standard example of that involves asynchronous calls to a number of remote services and computation of the answer once all of the responses are collected:
def price(itemId: Id): Future[Price] = ??? def availability(itemId: Id): Future[Int] = ??? def orderQuote(itemId: Id, quantityRequired: Int): Future[Option[Price]] = for { unitPrice &amp;lt;- price(itemId) quantityAvailable &amp;lt;- availability(itemId) } yield if (quantityAvailable &amp;gt;= quantityRequired) Some(quantityRequired * unitPrice) else None Here price and availability are service calls that can potentially take long time and are meant to be executed in parallel.</description></item><item><title>Duża wyspa, nie Sycylia</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/du%C5%BCa-wyspa-nie-sycylia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/du%C5%BCa-wyspa-nie-sycylia/</guid><description>Urlop nas zaskoczył, nie spodziewaliśmy się go w końcu sierpnia. W sierpniu jeździ się na urlop jak się ma dzieci, albo jak jest się miłośnikiem Central Line w godzinach szczytu i chce się przenieść doznania sardynki w puszce na plaże Costa Blanca lub do klubów Ibizy. Jakby się jednak chwilę zastanowić, ostatni tydzień sierpnia był nieunikniony, zbiegły się bowiem wówczas termin oddania pracy i koniec kontraktu. Nie zastanawialiśmy się najwidoczniej, bo wyszło tak, że zorientowaliśmy się na dwa tygodnie przed terminem – a dwa tygodnie przed terminem w sierpniu, to jak ostatni moment.</description></item><item><title>Glosariusz z północnych rubieży</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/glosariusz-z-p%C3%B3%C5%82nocnych-rubie%C5%BCy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/glosariusz-z-p%C3%B3%C5%82nocnych-rubie%C5%BCy/</guid><description>Wróciłem właśnie z Northumberland, na pograniczu angielsko-szkockim, i jestem strasznie zmachany. Szedłem przez dwa dni lasami, mokradłami i pagórkami, nigdzie żywej duszy, bolały mnie nogi od chodzenia, ramiona i biodra od noszenia plecaka, dieta marchewkowo-bananowo-suszonokiełbasiana wychodziła mi bokiem, rano albo siąpiła mżawka, albo było zimno i nie chciało się wychylać nosa ze śpiwora, chyba się przeziębiłem, a zupełnym już skandalem jest to, że przypiekło mnie słońce, choć ani na chwilę nie wyszło zza grubej warstwy chmur.</description></item><item><title>Functional Programming Exchange 2013</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/functional-programming-exchange-2013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/functional-programming-exchange-2013/</guid><description>After slightly disappointing FPX 2012, this year’s edition of Skills Matter-run one day gathering of functional programming enthusiasts bounced back with promising speaker line-up. The participant numbers were up compared to last year and seem to have even exceeded the excellent 2011 edition.
Adventures with Types in Haskell If anyone had any doubt about the reputation Simon Peyton Jones enjoys in fuctional programming community, the enthusiastic welcome he received must have dispelled it.</description></item><item><title>A Proper Fruit Salad</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/a-proper-fruit-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/a-proper-fruit-salad/</guid><description>Fruit salads do not enjoy a good reputation, and perhaps deservedly so. At supermarkets and sandwich joints, what passes as a “fruit salad” is usually nothing more than some random pieces of fruit approaching use-by date diced and sealed in a plastic container. At restaurants, dietetic martyrs who with sad resignation skim through the dessert menu and then announce they will have a fruit salad, attract sympathetic looks and knowing nods.</description></item><item><title>Pig's Legs in Aspic</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</guid><description>I am a fussy eater. When at primary school, I refused to partake of the simple and filling lunches we were served at the canteen, and when asked by a concerned lunch lady what the hell I am eating at home reportedly responded with veal fillet and fries. That was in soviet-era Poland, mind you, where meat was rationed, citizens were prepared to queue for hours to get hold of a frozen carcass of starved and abused chicken and brawls were commonly breaking out over who gets the right to buy the last paper-filled frankfurter.</description></item><item><title>Five Languages</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/five-languages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/five-languages/</guid><description>Pick three to five programming languages for teaching orthogonal programming paradigms. Which did you choose? Why? Blog and I&amp;#39;ll share.
&amp;mdash; Rosetta Code (@rosettacode) January 12, 2013 Interesting you should ask that, Rosetta Code. I’ve been pondering similar questions before, most recently inspired by Bruce Tate’s Seven Languages in Seven Weeks, whose languages of choice were sometimes overlapping (e.g. Io and Ruby) while leaving certain areas, such as concatenative languages, unexplored.</description></item><item><title>Dekalog</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dekalog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dekalog/</guid><description>I. nie będziesz całego pobytu w Tel Avivie spędzał na plaży Garie to to nie jest. Fale niewielkie, a przyjemność z pluskania się psują pojawiające się niekiedy ławice fragmentów foliowych torebek i innego śmiecia. Wzdłuż plaży ciągnie się dość ruchliwa ulica, za nią stoi rząd wielkich hoteli. Tym niemniej, można tam przyjemnie spędzić godzinkę albo dwie, trochę mocząc się i pływając w osłoniętych falochronami obaszarach, trochę piekąc się na słońcu. Piasek przyjemny (choć sporo w nim papierosowych petów), co kilkaset metrów znaleźć można knajpę serwującą zimne napoje, miejscowa młodzież bawi się odbijając twarde piłeczki dużymi, drewnianymi paletkami, a młodzież młodsza buduje na brzegu zamki z piasku; nieźle, jak na centrum milionowego miasta.</description></item><item><title>Tesco Finest Salad</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</guid><description>After moving to London to live on my own, I rented a one bed flat located on the top floor of a 16-story high tower block. It was a 1970s, local authority building, and the unquestionable advantages of awesome view over the city, proximity to work and affordability were somewhat counterbalanced by extreme heat in the summer, biting cold in the winter and the council tenants taking their bull terriers to relieve themselves in the lift.</description></item><item><title>Dziennik islandzki</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dziennik-islandzki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/dziennik-islandzki/</guid><description>Poniedziałek Tyle się teraz wozi ze sobą dupereli, że co i rusz zapomni się o czymś ważnym. Powtarzam sobie, że grunt, żeby paszport i pieniądze były, resztę się da zorganizować na miejscu, a tu bach – zapominam karty PADI (Ania też nie wzięła), i główny punkt programu stoi pod dużym znakiem zapytania. Przypomniałem sobie w autobusie z lotniska w Keflavik do Reykjaviku, i natychmiast wysłałem maila do firmy organizującej nurkowania w Silfra.</description></item><item><title>Wild Boar Fillet à la Białowieża</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/wild-boar-fillet-%C3%A0-la-bia%C5%82owie%C5%BCa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/wild-boar-fillet-%C3%A0-la-bia%C5%82owie%C5%BCa/</guid><description>There is often that one ingredient. You’re in a supermarket and a vegetable you don’t normally eat catches your eye, or it’s a jar of some obscure substance that suddenly seems like a promising kernel around which you can build a dinner. Or, it’s something rare, that you got from someone and sits in your pantry waiting for that moment of inspiration. This evening’s dish is going to be of this kind.</description></item><item><title>Test of Github as a Tutorial Hosting Platform - Literate Specifications with specs2</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/test-of-github-as-a-tutorial-hosting-platform-literate-specifications-with-specs2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/test-of-github-as-a-tutorial-hosting-platform-literate-specifications-with-specs2/</guid><description>This is an experiment with how well Github is suited to host coding tutorials. Turns out that the navigation and presentation could be a bit better, but overall it seems to be fairly usable. And since the tutorial has the form of a git repository, we are not restricted to using Github, but can come up with software that is specifically designed to present the subsequent commits as steps of a tutorial… clearly, DVCS and self-contained repositories are very powerful ideas.</description></item><item><title>せっかちな人のためのうどん</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/%E3%81%9B%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8B%E3%81%A1%E3%81%AA%E4%BA%BA%E3%81%AE%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E3%81%86%E3%81%A9%E3%82%93/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/%E3%81%9B%E3%81%A3%E3%81%8B%E3%81%A1%E3%81%AA%E4%BA%BA%E3%81%AE%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E3%81%86%E3%81%A9%E3%82%93/</guid><description>For people of occidental origin such as myself, the first degree of initiation in Wagamama’s menu is invariably Chicken Katsu Curry. Those who dare to abandon the comfortable familiarity of breaded chicken, rice, and sauce not altogether unlike the gravy often served with traditional English pies will arrive in the land of wok-fried udon noodles – that’s the second degree, and this what I have so far achieved. I can only guess what happens further, but would venture a supposition that one must at some point attain the level of a bowl of ramen, which, according to Wagamama’s own advertising, seems to be what every fashionable young person orders there.</description></item><item><title>The Making of a Burrito</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-making-of-a-burrito/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-making-of-a-burrito/</guid><description>A couple of years ago a new take-away moved into what used to be a dental practice directly beneath the platform of a Docklands Light Railway station. The establishment called itself “Tortilla” – a fitting, if somewhat unimaginative name for a place that sells burritos. Given that it was just next door to where I used to work at the time, it didn’t take me – a long-time chilli con carne buff – to become a regular.</description></item><item><title>Pollo con Pancetta alla Avanzi</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pollo-con-pancetta-alla-avanzi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pollo-con-pancetta-alla-avanzi/</guid><description>For quite a while I have been relying on recipes scavenged from various corners of the web, with little added creativity. There are some which I would like to share my take on, like Jamie’s fish linguine – I even have a nice photo taken already – but going for something so much borrowed would require considerable literary embellishment, which recently I have felt incapable of.
So, Jamie’s fish will have to wait; meanwhile, leftovers to the rescue of creative spirit!</description></item><item><title>TN</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tn/</guid><description>Jacka Danielsa tu nie uświadczysz. W knajpach królują piwa: koncernowe i paskudne Budy i Millery oraz ciekawe ales (India Pale, Amber, Dark) z mikrobrowarów. W liquor store też bardziej w oczy rzucają się słoiki z lokalnym bimbrem niż kwadratowe butelki z czarną etykietą. Krainę whiskey wyobrażałem sobie1 jako nie kończące się pola jęczmienia, kukurydzy, i czego tam jescze nie używają do produkcji Jacka, tymczasem zobaczyliśmy wzgórza i lasy a też i całkiem pokaźne góry.</description></item><item><title>Scala LiftOff London 2011 - Day 1</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2011-day-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2011-day-1/</guid><description>Compared to last year’s LiftOff, which was an un-conference pretty much all the way, this year’s is split into morning, structured sessions, and afternoon open spaces resembling 2010 format. As usual, I tried to jot down the more interesting points from the day. The below is by no means a complete record and definitely suffers from insufficient editing and research (no time for that, sorry!). With this disclaimer out of the way:</description></item><item><title>Setting up BuildBot with Windows Slave on AWS EC2</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/setting-up-buildbot-with-windows-slave-on-aws-ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/setting-up-buildbot-with-windows-slave-on-aws-ec2/</guid><description>Not long ago I set up a BuildBot instance for wxHaskell and thought about sharing my experience with configuring all the elements of the system. Johan Tibell’s commentary to the State of Haskell, 2011 survey, and his call for Windows bots to test Hackage libraries, prompted me to finally put my notes together into tutorial of a sort. There is nothing Haskell-specific, so if you are looking to automate Windows builds of apps written in any other language this guide should provide all the info you need.</description></item><item><title>Scala Exchange 2011 - Day 1</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-exchange-2011-day-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-exchange-2011-day-1/</guid><description>I’ve attended a day full of Scala-related talks at Scala Exchange 2011, and, as was the case with the previous events organised by SkillsMatter, I felt that relating what was said and what my impressions were will help me digest all the new pieces of information. So, here it goes.
State of Scala In the keynote talk Martin Odersky explained how his perception of usefulness of functional programming in the real world shifted from a good fit for XML manipulation to concurrent and parallel computing.</description></item><item><title>Functional Programming Exchange 2011</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/functional-programming-exchange-2011/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/functional-programming-exchange-2011/</guid><description>After the success that Scala LiftOff London 2010 was I didn’t hesitate long before signing up for a number of other Scala and functional programming events hosted by Skills Matter. The first of them was Functional Programming Exchange. Below are notes from most of the sessions of this one-day conference.
Managing Parallelism - Embrace Diversity The event started with Simon Peyton Jones discussing the importance of parallel computing, how different problems call for different approaches and how functional languages (and Haskell in particular) are well suited for the task.</description></item><item><title>Haskell MVC</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-mvc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/haskell-mvc/</guid><description>with wxHaskell and STM
With popularity of Haskell raising in recent years I have decided to have a look at how suitable it is as a general-purpose programming language. The experiment involves writing a Windows client for FIBS.
It turned out to be far from easy.
It might be down to my lack of familiarity with functional programming patterns. Or perhaps, despite growing popularity, there are still no established FP GUI patterns yet.</description></item><item><title>Po powrocie</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/po-powrocie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/po-powrocie/</guid><description>30 stycznia, zgodnie z planem wróciliśmy do domu. Minęły od tego czasu dwa tygodnie, wypadałoby więć jakoś go podsumować zanim wszystko wyleci z głowy. Wycieczka spełniła wszystkie moje oczekiwania i nawet rezygnacji z Fraser Island i Gold Coast nie wspominam z żalem, bo dzięki temu zobaczylismy australijski outback. A co dokładnie było takie fajne? Jakie pomysły się nie sprawdziły?
Pomysły Poniżej trzy listy. Pierwsza zawiera rzeczy, które może nie są oczywiste (jak Angkor Wat czy Wielka Rafa), ale godne polecenia, zapadające w pamięć jako coś fajnego.</description></item><item><title>Roasted Root Vegetables</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/roasted-root-vegetables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/roasted-root-vegetables/</guid><description>Commonly when preparing the main course we start with the choice of meat (if any) and the way to cook it, and then treat the vegetables, rice etc. as an addition. For today’s course I’m doing something opposite: make vegetables the cetrepiece, with meat acting as a side dish. The first time I ate something similar was in December 2009 in Lapland, with -30°C outside, so somehow naturally I associate it with winter.</description></item><item><title>Singapur</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/singapur/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/singapur/</guid><description>Singapur to już ostatni przystanek na naszej trasie. Zatrzymaliśmy się tu na trzy dni; Ania chciała jeszcze trochę skorzystać ze wody i słońca, ja powałęsać się po mieście. Woda owszem, była, nawet w dużych ilościach, jednak nie w formie, na jaką liczyliśmy, bo leciała z chmur. Słońce też się pojawiało, ale z reguły nie wtedy, kiedy woda; Ania była niepocieszona.
Wałęsanie się wychodziło nieco lepiej. Pierwszego dnia obeszliśmy Chinatown, nadbrzeże przy sali koncertowej (zwanej durianem, ze względu na przypominający ten owoc kolczasty dach) i centrum biznesowe, kolejnego zajrzeliśmy do tonącego w strugach deszczu Little India.</description></item><item><title>Sydney</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/sydney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/sydney/</guid><description>Jeśli przypadkiem znajdziecie się w Sydney na kilka dni i nie będziecie mieli pomysłu, co z tym czasem zrobić, możecie wybrać kilka pozycji z menu poniżej. Wszystkie przetestowaliśmy osobiście; przy atrakcjach płatnych podajemy orientacyjne ceny za jedną osobę oraz czas, który są w stanie zagospodarować.
Stek z kangura. Kangurów niby jest w Australii zatrzęsienie, ale restauracji serwujących mięso tych zwierząt nie ma wcale tak wiele, a jeśli akurat macie pecha i w Queensland, które jest głównym dostawcą kangurzyny dla Sydney, jest akurat powódź stulecia, może się okazać, że znalezienie tego specjału graniczy z cudem.</description></item><item><title>Trzy plaże</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/trzy-pla%C5%BCe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/trzy-pla%C5%BCe/</guid><description>Po Górach Błękitnych dotarliśmy do Sydney i choć zostało nam jeszcze kilka dni rozbijania się naszym zielonym vanem, kronika naszej trasy tu się zakończy. Kręcić się teraz będziemy w okolicach Sydney i mniej czasu spędzać będziemy w samochodzie a więcej na zwiedzaniu ciekawych miejsc, stąd odmienny od wcześniejszych charakter niniejszego wpisu.
Zapanowała ostatnio moda, nawet w poważnej prasie, na recenzje pisane przez osoby skąd inąd znane, lecz w dziedzinie, której dotyczy recenzja, będące ignorantami.</description></item><item><title>Są góry, to musi być zimno</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/s%C4%85-g%C3%B3ry-to-musi-by%C4%87-zimno/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/s%C4%85-g%C3%B3ry-to-musi-by%C4%87-zimno/</guid><description>17 stycznia park narodowy Warrumbungle – Lithgow, 4362 – 4773 kilometr Noc spędzona na parkingu w parku narodowym Warrumbungle była pierwszą od dawien dawna, podczas której nie dokuczały nam komary. Panował też przyjemny chłód – wjechaliśmy w niewielkie góry, nasz nocleg położony był 500 metrów nad poziomem morza. Jedyny mankament to fakt, że nocowaliśmy na terenie parku bez uiszczenia stosownej opłaty, w związku z czym musieliśmy się zebrać dość wcześnie rano, żeby nas przypadkiem strażnicy nie namierzyli.</description></item><item><title>Przez outback</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/przez-outback/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/przez-outback/</guid><description>13 stycznia okolice Clermont – Barcaldine, 2440 – 2907 kilometr W Clermont dowiadujemy się, że droga z Balcardine na południe jest zamknięta w Charleville. Stawia to pod znakiem zapytania nasz plan jazdy do Nowej Południowej Walii. Od czego jednak jest plan C? Uderzymy przez Mount Isa do Alice Springs w Terytorium Północnym (to jedyne 1500 km), zobaczymy te słynną wielką pustynię oraz Uluru, czyli największy głaz na ziemi, a później już pojedziemy wprost do Sydney – to raptem niecałe 2800 km!</description></item><item><title>Ucieczka na zachód</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ucieczka-na-zach%C3%B3d/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ucieczka-na-zach%C3%B3d/</guid><description>9 stycznia Lake Eacham – okolice Woodstock, 442 – 909 kilometr O szóstej rano można było nas zastać w parku na ławce nad rzeczką, w ciszy i skupieniu wpatrujących się w taflę wody. Nie staliśmy się bynajmniej miłośnikami wędkowania; próbowaliśmy dojrzeć dziobaki, które podobno żerują w tym miejscu. Na próżno – pora roku nie jest po temu najlepsza, a dziobaki to bardzo płochliwe stowrzenia
Szczęścia do dużych egzemplarzy tutejszej fauny póki co nie mamy.</description></item><item><title>Wilgotne tropiki</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wilgotne-tropiki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wilgotne-tropiki/</guid><description>6 stycznia Cairns – Cape Tribulation, 0 – 162 kilometr Przed południem odebraliśmy 434 MZX z biura w centrum Cairns, dokąd z Kubą wybraliśmy się z naszego couchsurfingowego locum na piechotę. Mój apel o nadanie pojazdowi pięknej nazwy, na wzór okrętów i statków kosmicznych, został zignorowany (a szkoda; o ile bardziej dostojnie brzmiałoby: “Z dziennika pokładowego Endavour” albo “Z dziennika pokładowego Bee’s Knees”!), pozostaniemy więc przy identyfikatorze, który nadało mu państwo australijskie, a może stan Queensland, nie wiem dokładnie jak się tu rzeczy mają.</description></item><item><title>Dwa dni w mokrych gaciach</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/dwa-dni-w-mokrych-gaciach/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/dwa-dni-w-mokrych-gaciach/</guid><description>Rekina przegapić się nie dało. Był niepokaźnych rozmiarów, długi może na metr, z białym czubkiem płetwy – normalnie możnaby na niego nie zwrócić uwagi, ale teraz światło sześciu latarek było zwrócone właśnie na jego podłużny korpus, wszędzie indziej była nieprzenikniona ciemność. Przypomniałem sobie instrukcję obrony przed rekinem: oświetlić się latarką, żeby zobaczył, jaki jestem duży – wtedy przestanę dla niego być atrakcyjny jako pokarm. Manewr ten okazał się tym razem niepotrzebny; rekin, po początkowym zainteresowaniu światłem latarek, odpłynął w siną (a raczej czarną) dal.</description></item><item><title>Powrót do cywilizacji</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/powr%C3%B3t-do-cywilizacji/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/powr%C3%B3t-do-cywilizacji/</guid><description>Zakończyliśmy już azjatycką część naszej przygody. Po Sylwestrze w Sajgonie i pożegnaniu z Trungiem i Justyną, pierwszego stycznia rano zapakowaliśmy się w samolot do Singapuru, skąd, tego samego dnia wieczorem, wylecieliśmy do Australii.
Siedząc w Starbucksie w Plaza Singapura i wyglądając na zalaną deszczem Orchard Road czułem się zabawnie. W mieście tym gościłem przez dwa tygodnie ponad trzy lata temu i nie powiedziałbym, że się w jakikolwiek sposób z nim zżyłem, jednak teraz, po czterech tygodniach podróży przez kompletnie obce miejsca czułem się jakbym po raz pierwszy od piętnastu lat odwiedzał budynek swojej podstawówki.</description></item><item><title>Rzemieślnicza Republika Wietnamu</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/rzemie%C5%9Blnicza-republika-wietnamu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/rzemie%C5%9Blnicza-republika-wietnamu/</guid><description>Diamond Shopping Mall znajduje się przy jednej z najbardziej reprezentacyjnych ulich Sajgonu, biegnącej od frontu Pałacu Zjednoczenia. Na parterze tego ekskluzywnego centrum handlowego kupić można perfumy Chanel, Gucci i innych cenionych marek. Kolejne piętra oferują ubrania od najsłynniejszych projektantów, zegarki Rolex i Omega i inne luksusowe akcesoria. Podobnie jak marki, ceny są dla przybysza z Zachodu znajome: od dziesiątków dolarów za flakony perfum po tysiące za kreacje i zegarki.
Dwudziestominutowy spacer na południe, najpierw ulicą Pasteura a później w prawo, w Le Loi, zaprowadzi nas do Bien Thanh.</description></item><item><title>Z Hanoi do Sajgonu</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/z-hanoi-do-sajgonu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/z-hanoi-do-sajgonu/</guid><description>Pisanie niniejszego sprawozdania wyglądać miało tak, że po dniu zwiedzania, usadowiwszy się w pokoju hotelowym, przez dwie lub trzy godziny spisuję wrażenia i przemyślenia w ciekawej i pomysłowej formie. Rzeczywistość okazuje się nieco inna; za wyjątkiem Don Khon i Vientiane, gdzie mieliśmy parę dni wytchnienia, reszta wycieczki to maraton: zwiedzanie, szukanie hoteli, szukanie transportu do następnego miejsca, jazda autobusami itd. Trudno wykroić wystarczającą ilość czasu żeby pomyśleć jak i o czym napisać – pozostaje pożegnać się z inteligentną formą i po prostu notować naprędce to, co się wydarzyło – zanim się wszystko pozapomina.</description></item><item><title>Wigilia w Hanoi</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wigilia-w-hanoi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wigilia-w-hanoi/</guid><description>Aż trudno uwierzyć, że od naszego przylotu do Hanoi minęły tylko trzy dni. Tyle się w tym czasie wydarzyło, że trudno wszystko spamiętać, obawiam się więc, że niniejsze sprawozdanie będzie sprawiało wrażenie poszatkowanego i przeładowanego – spróbujmy jednak zrelacjonować co najważniejsze. Trung, gdy się z nim umawialiśmy na spotkanie, stwierdził, że “mama wszystko załatwi”. Nie wiedzieliśmy czego się spodziewać; przed naszym wylotem z Vientiane do Hanoi dowiedzieliśmy się jedynie, że hotel mamy już załatwiony i opłacony – o zwrocie kosztów mowy nie było – i żeby tam się po przylocie udać.</description></item><item><title>Azja po dwóch tygodniach</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/azja-po-dw%C3%B3ch-tygodniach/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/azja-po-dw%C3%B3ch-tygodniach/</guid><description>Vientiane jest zabawne. Ma fontanny, które włączane są tylko gdy nieopodal przejeżdżają kolumny samochodów z oficjelami, i Champs-Élysées z żelbetowym łukiem triumfalnym, w którym mieszczą się stragany z pamiątkami. Poza tym jest to miasto nad wyraz kameralne i spokojne. Lenimy się tu, wałęsając się po mieście, szukając biżuterii i ozdób do kostiumów tanecznych i nadrabiając zaległości we wgrywaniu zdjęć na Flickr. Korzystając z braku wydarzeń do zrelacjonowania podzielę się więc spostrzeżeniami dotyczącymi tego kawałka Azji, który do tej pory udało nam się zobaczyć.</description></item><item><title>Jedna z czterech tysięcy</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/jedna-z-czterech-tysi%C4%99cy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/jedna-z-czterech-tysi%C4%99cy/</guid><description>Właściciel wrócił po jakichś dwudziestu minutach. Na kierownicy motoroweru wisiała torba z jajkami i czymś, co wyglądało jak dynia. Ze świeżo zakupionymi wiktuałami udał się do znajdującej się za przepierzeniem z bambusowej plecionki kuchni i po chwili dało się słyszeć odgłosy przygotowywania naszego śniadania: naleśnika z ananasem i omletu z dynią. Siedzimy pod opartym na ażurowej konstrukcji z bambusowych pali dachem krytym ryżową słomą. Prócz nas w lokalu jest tylko dziesięcioletnia może córka właściciela, oglądająca w telewizji jakąś lokalną telenowelę i bawiąca się z małym kotem o przykrótkim, poskręcanym ogonie.</description></item><item><title>Phnom Penh</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/phnom-penh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/phnom-penh/</guid><description>Phnom Penh to druga, po Bangkoku, azjatycka stolica, którą przyszło nam odwiedzić. Jest od głównego miasta Tajlandii znacznie mniej turystyczna, kierowcy tuk tuków nie są natarczywi, można się przespacerować wzdłuż rzeki (w Bangkoku nabrzeże jest zabudowane) i generalnie jest jakby bardziej kameralnie, autentycznie i sympatycznie. Nas sprowadziły tu przede wszystkim dwie pamiątki po Czerwonych Khmerach: muzeum w osławionym więzieniu Toul Sleng i tzw. “pola śmierci” w Choeung Ek, pod miastem.</description></item><item><title>Angkor</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/angkor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/angkor/</guid><description>Po opuszczeniu parku Khao Yai przedostaliśmy się przez granicę, dotarliśmy do Siem Reap, spotkaliśmy się z od dawna nie widzianą przyjaciółką z Japonii, uczciliśmy urodziny Marty i odwiedziliśmy jeden z głównych punktów naszej wizyty w Azji, ruiny świątyń z okresu świetności królestwa Khmerów. Angkor Wat zobaczyć na pewno warto, choć trzeba być przygotowanym na to, że pomimo niezbyt dogodnej lokalizacji turystów przybywają tam tysiące i że proponowane standardowo sposoby zwiedzania nie mają wiele sensu.</description></item><item><title>Park narodowy Khao Yai</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/park-narodowy-khao-yai/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/park-narodowy-khao-yai/</guid><description>Do Pak Chong dotarliśmy zgodnie z planem i bez większych przygód. Do mniejszych zaliczyć można taksówkę, która zaczęła nas wieźć na nie tę stację kolejową, ale zapas czasu wystarczył na korektę i skończyło się jedynie na rachunku dwa razy wyższym, niż zakładaliśmy (lecz wciąż o połowę niższym niż wywoławcza cena tuktukersów z Khao San, ktorzy zawsze mówią “200”, dokąd by się nie chciało jechać). Dalej poszło gładko: wsiedliśmy w ten pociąg co trzeba, w Ayutthaya dosiedli się Kuba z Martą, udało nam się też wysiąść na właściwej stacji.</description></item><item><title>Bangkok</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/bangkok/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/bangkok/</guid><description>Do Bangkoku dotarliśmy przed siódmą rano, po jedenastogodzinnym locie, podczas którego przespałem może godzinę, tak że plan bezbolesnego przestawiania czasu diabli wzięli. Miejsca mieliśmy całkiem sporo, cały, trzymiejscowy rząd dla nas dwojga, ale nie sposób było znaleźć pozycji, w której dałoby się usnąć. Fotele w klasie biznes mają jednak tę istotną przewagę, że można z nich zrobić w pełni funkcjonalne łóżko. Jakoś dolecieliśmy, i kolejny etap stanowiło uzyskanie wizy do Tajlandii.</description></item><item><title>Ostatni tydzień przed wyjazdem</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ostatni-tydzie%C5%84-przed-wyjazdem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ostatni-tydzie%C5%84-przed-wyjazdem/</guid><description>Mam obawy, że ilość dywagacji nie na temat, którymi w ostatnim czasie okraszam ten blog, powoduje, że staje się on dla czytelników niestrawny. Z drugiej jednak strony muza (Klio to czy Kalliope?) najwyraźniej nie daje spokoju i wena twórcza musi znaleźć gdzieś ujście. Postanowiłem przeprowadzić więc eksperyment: nagłówki akapitów stanowią słowa kluczowe, z których wyczytać można, co się dzieje, a to, co pomiędzy nimi, to wypełniacz ze standardową dawką wodolejstwa.</description></item><item><title>Wymiękanie noclegowe</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wymi%C4%99kanie-noclegowe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/wymi%C4%99kanie-noclegowe/</guid><description>Zacząć się może tak pięknie. Wyśpiwszy się w samolocie przybywamy w do Bangkoku, wkraczamy do hotelu na Khao San road, oglądamy pokój, kręcimy nosem, w końcu zniesmaczeni wychodzimy, wchodzimy do innego, tam, wiedząc, na co powinniśmy być przygotowani, od razu podajemy cenę cztery razy niższą niż zaoferowana, i twardo negocjując pozbawiamy hotelarzy argumentów aż w końcu muszą oddać nam swój najlepszy pokój za połowę ceny. Wszystko razem zajmuje piętnaście minut, po upływie których idziemy na miasto i zażywamy uroków stolicy Tajlandii.</description></item><item><title>Na zdrowie</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/na-zdrowie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/na-zdrowie/</guid><description>Zajmowanie się sprawami zdrowotnymi przed wyjazdem to dla mnie zupełna nowość. Zawsze byłem zdania, że apteczki i lekarstwa to bezużyteczny ciężar, który zajmuje tylko miejsce w bagażu, zmniejsza szansę znalezienia w kieszeni plecaka tego, czego się akurat szuka i dodatkowo może przysporzyć kłopotów przy kontrolach granicznych, bo substancje dozwolone tu mogą być surowo zakazane tam, i na odwrót. Poza tym wiadomo, że najlepszym sposobem na chorobę jest udawać, że jej nie ma.</description></item><item><title>Ekwipunek tropikalny</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ekwipunek-tropikalny/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/ekwipunek-tropikalny/</guid><description>Przy okazji wcześniejszych wyjazdów zgromadziliśmy sporo sprzętu turystycznego: plecaki, kurtki, buty itp. Jako że nasze wycieczki ograniczały się dotychczas do Europy, a w ostatnich latach właściwie wyłącznie do Anglii, wyposażenie to przystosowane jest do innego nieco klimatu niż ten, który nas czeka w Azji i Australii. Ponadto charakter wyprawy będzie dość zróżnicowany: sporo czasu planujemy spędzać w miastach i miasteczkach Kambodży i Wietnamu, kilka tygodni w samochodzie, być może kilka dni w dżungli.</description></item><item><title>Itinerer</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/itinerer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/itinerer/</guid><description>Mały suplement do poprzedniego odcinka, czyli gdzie kiedy planujemy być:
kiedy co 5-6 lot Londyn — Bangkok 6-7 Bangkok 8-9 Khao Yai 10 w drodze do Siem Reap 11-12 Angkor Wat 13 w drodze do Phnom Penh 14-15 Phnom Penh 15 w drodze do Laosu 16-18 4000 wysp 19 w drodze do Vientiane 20-22 Vientiane 23 w drodze do Hanoi 24-26 zatoka Halong 27-31 z Hanoi do Sajgonu 1-2 loty Sajgon — Singapur oraz Singapur — Darwin — Cairns 3-5 Wielka Rafa 6-24 z Cairns do Sydney 25 Sydney 26 lot Sydney — Darwin — Singapur 27-28 Singapur 29-30 lot Singapur — Kuala Lumpur — Londyn</description></item><item><title>Trasa</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/trasa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wyprawa-2010-11/trasa/</guid><description>Jedziemy na wakacje! O dłuższej przerwie myślałem od jakichś dwóch lat i po licznych perypetiach, rezygnacji z ambitnych planów podróży z Alaski do Terra del Fuego, bojach Ani o urlop i zawirowaniach związanych z moją pracą stanęło na tym, że piątego grudnia wyjeżdżamy na osiem tygodni do Azji południowo-wschodniej i Australii.
Na początku tego roku, po ustaleniu, że do dyspozycji mamy około dwóch miesięcy, krystalizować zaczęły się pomysły na trasę: początkowo była to jazda samochodem z zachodu na wschód Australii, później do planu dołączyła Nowa Zelandia, w następnej kolejności fragmenty Azji południowo-wschodniej, które byłyby po drodze.</description></item><item><title>Scala LiftOff London 2010 - Day 2</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2010-day-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2010-day-2/</guid><description>← Day One
The second and last day of Scala Lift Off did not disappoint. Compared to yesterday, the sessions I attended turned out to be less focussed on presenting concrete projects or results and more on discussing the language features and tools from the position of users discovering them. Overall, less structure, more interaction.
Teasers The day started with half an hour of very short talks by authors of a number of Scala-based projects.</description></item><item><title>Scala LiftOff London 2010 - Day 1</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2010-day-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/scala-liftoff-london-2010-day-1/</guid><description>The first day of this year’s Scala Lift Off London exceeded my modest expectations. It was full of excellent presentations and interesting discussions attended by very friendly folk. I trust tomorrow will not be worse; in the mean time here are some notes from the sessions I attended.
Session 1: From Java to Scala Graham Tackley of guardian.co.uk told us about the experience of his team with embracing Scala. Guardian.co.uk had been a Java shop and when a project to provide API to access all of their content had been started their technology stack of choice was Java, Guice and Apache Solr.</description></item><item><title>E-mail Testing with Mock SMTP Server</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/e-mail-testing-with-mock-smtp-server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/e-mail-testing-with-mock-smtp-server/</guid><description>If our application can send e-mail (and, according to Letts’ Law, it eventually will), we would want our integration tests to verify that the e-mail has indeed been sent, and that its contents are as expected. If we have written the integration tests in Python this will be pretty straightforward: Python library provides smtpd package with an implementation of SMTP server class, all we need to do is extend it to store the received messages and provide a way for the test code to verify that message has indeed been received.</description></item><item><title>Integration Testing with TeamCity</title><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/integration-testing-with-teamcity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/integration-testing-with-teamcity/</guid><description>Inspired by a recent seminar Ken Schwaber presented at the company I work for, I decided to provide the means for ensuring that the high-level functionality of an application package built in our continuous integration environment (we use TeamCity) can be tested automatically.
The Context Suppose we are working on a stand-alone java app (let’s call it tc-rec, after the app I have been setting up integration tests for) and have an existing build which generates a zip file containing all the jars and scripts required to run the app.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/powr%C3%B3t-do-dartmoor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/powr%C3%B3t-do-dartmoor/</guid><description>Powrót do Dartmoor Date: April 23, 2017 Tags: England, Food, National Park, Walk
Po jedenastu latach wróciliśmy do Dartmoor. Patrząc na zdjęcia, niewiele się zmieniło: te same trzęsawiska, karłowate, omszałe drzewa, kamienne pozostałości z epoki brązu, ciężkie chmury. Wiatr. Przed jedenastu laty nosiłem bandanę zasłaniającą ucho, w które wiało; teraz chodzę w czapce i nieprzewiewnych bluzach. Zmieniliśmy się my: jesteśmy, mówiąc oględnie, bardziej dojrzali. Zamiast wielkich plecaków z karimatami i namiotem mamy samochód – wynajęty, bo nasz, świeżo po wymianie silnika, był zbyt niepewnym środkiem lokomocji na pięćsetkilometrową podróż.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/przyroda-i-arystokracja/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/przyroda-i-arystokracja/</guid><description>Przyroda i arystokracja Date: May 16, 2018 Tags: Castle, England, Forest, National Park, Walk, Wildlife
W zeszłym roku Z. wpadła na pomysł, żeby kupić samochód i robić sobie długoweekendowe wypady do parków narodowych. No więc kupiłem, trzynastoletniego Forda StreetKa, któremu po pięciu minutach jazdy wystrzeliła uszczelka z pod głowicy, tak że później bałem się nim jechać dalej niż 10 mil, i ostatecznie sprzedałem go dwóm Rumunom za 300 funtów. Do parków tym niemniej jeździmy, wynajętymi autami, co ma same prawie zalety: wychodzi taniej, samochody są nowiutkie, i można sobie zrobić testy jak się z różnymi autami żyje.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/robale-z-wharfedale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/robale-z-wharfedale/</guid><description>Robale z Wharfedale Date: April 28, 2019 Tags: City, England, Food, Pub, Walk, Wine
W Yorkshire Dales byliśmy po raz pierwszy. Obawiałem się, że na północy Anglii pogoda może nie dopisać, ale weekend wielkanocny był słoneczny i bardzo ciepły również tam; do tego stopnia, że Z się przegrzewała, i musieliśmy robić dłuższe postoje w cieniu.
Pętla z Kettlewell Mieszkaliśmy w Kettlewell. Myślałem, żeby w sobotę rano wstać wcześnie, pojechać do Ribblesdale, zaparkować gdzieś i z tamtąd zrobić pętlę przez największą górę regionu, Pen-y-ghent, ale szczęśliwie poszedłem po rozum do głowy i zdecydowałem jednak przejść się po Wharfedale.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/stolica-europy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/stolica-europy/</guid><description>Stolica Europy Date: December 3, 2012 Tags: Beer, Belgium, City, Europe, Food, Weekend
Z Brukseli pamiętam koronkowy Grote Markt i kupę restauracji zachęcających apetycznymi menu. Zawitałem tu w 2001 roku, na InterRailu, z miesięcznym budżetem w wysokości 500 złotych. Byłem w tym czasie zafascynowany Gryphonem, i gdy czwartego dnia po wyjeździe z Warszawy mieliśmy krótki postój w Hamburgu, zaopatrzyłem się w szałamaję.
Przez resztę podróży bezskutecznie próbowałem wydobyć z niej jakiś dźwięk, aż w końcu stroik się rozsechł, i tyle było zabawy.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/surfing-oraz-inne-zabawy-na-deszczowe-dni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/surfing-oraz-inne-zabawy-na-deszczowe-dni/</guid><description>Surfing, oraz inne zabawy na deszczowe dni Date: November 23, 2014 Tags: Beach, Camping, Canary Islands, Mountains, Sea
Muszość spowodowała, że wyruszyłem w tę podróż niezbyt przygotowany. Zapisałem się byłem bowiem na dwa kursy online, wymyśliłem też, że wystąpię na pewnej konferencji, słuchanie wykładów, rozwiązywanie zadań domowych oraz przygotowywanie wystąpienia nie pozostawiło już czasu na nic innego. Mógłbym sobie zapewne odpuścić przynajmniej część tych wykładów i zadań, lecz muszość nie pozwoliła.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Beehive in Basildon Date: May 31, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
It occurred to me that my long-held belief about lack of pubs in South-West Essex stemmed from a peculiar understanding of what a pub is. What I had in mind was a place that is local and quaint, has unique character and is a bit out of the beaten track. None of the pubs we visited so far had this feel, vindicating in some sense my earlier conviction.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-1/</guid><description>Ambience Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-2/</guid><description>Ambience Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-3/</guid><description>Ambience Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience-4/</guid><description>Ambience Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/ambience/</guid><description>Ambience Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-1/</guid><description>Availability of vegan food Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-2/</guid><description>Availability of vegan food Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-3/</guid><description>Availability of vegan food Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food-4/</guid><description>Availability of vegan food Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/availability-of-vegan-food/</guid><description>Availability of vegan food Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-1/</guid><description>Bathrooms Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-2/</guid><description>Bathrooms Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-3/</guid><description>Bathrooms Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms-4/</guid><description>Bathrooms Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/bathrooms/</guid><description>Bathrooms Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-1/</guid><description>Cheapness Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-2/</guid><description>Cheapness Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness-3/</guid><description>Cheapness Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/cheapness/</guid><description>Cheapness Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-1/</guid><description>Drinks Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-2/</guid><description>Drinks Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-3/</guid><description>Drinks Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks-4/</guid><description>Drinks Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/drinks/</guid><description>Drinks Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-1/</guid><description>Food quality Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-2/</guid><description>Food quality Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-3/</guid><description>Food quality Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality-4/</guid><description>Food quality Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/food-quality/</guid><description>Food quality Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-1/</guid><description>Service Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-2/</guid><description>Service Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-3/</guid><description>Service Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service-4/</guid><description>Service Pub: The Beehive in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/service/</guid><description>Service Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-1/</guid><description>Surroundings Pub: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-2/</guid><description>Surroundings Pub: The Beehive in Basildon</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-3/</guid><description>Surroundings Pub: The Quays in Basildon Rating: ★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings-4/</guid><description>Surroundings Pub: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Rating: ★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-beehive-in-basildon/the-z-scor/surroundings/</guid><description>Surroundings Pub: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Rating: ★★★</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-bell-in-horndon-on-the-hill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-bell-in-horndon-on-the-hill/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Bell in Horndon on the Hill Date: October 16, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
For many years my mental map of SW Essex contained just two good dining places: Magic Mushroom and The Bell. It still does, though I have not visited Magic Mushroom for a long time. The Bell used to be the place to take foreign visitors to, to show them a historic English pub and impress with fancy food.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-boars-head-in-herongate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-boars-head-in-herongate/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Boar&amp;rsquo;s Head in Herongate Date: June 29, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
A bonus pub visit this week. On the hottest day of the year so far, we went to Thorndon Country Park. It is a lovely area, where one can walk for hours among ancient woodland, dense rhododendron groves, forest clearings and meadows, or just lie down on a grass and read a book (which we did).</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-dog-and-partridge-in-orsett/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-dog-and-partridge-in-orsett/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett Date: June 26, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
Last Sunday I visited The Four Seasons again, to watch the England vs. Cameroon world cup game. There were some pleasant and unpleasant surprises. The pleasant one was that the ales on tap have changed, and they now had Yardbird pale ale, from Greene King, but pretty decent. The bad was that even though the game was shown on the TV screens around the bar, the sound was off and noone paid any attention.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-dukes-head-in-little-burstead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-dukes-head-in-little-burstead/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Duke&amp;rsquo;s Head in Little Burstead Date: August 13, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
We are approaching Billericay on our quest. Things are getting posh. Pastel-coloured walls, wrought iron fireplaces. Scallops for a starter. A burger for £16. But, let us not forget, this is still south Essex; the music is a bit too loud, the bar focuses on lagers at the expense of ales.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-four-seasons-in-laindon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-four-seasons-in-laindon/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Four Seasons in Laindon Date: May 1, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
I live in a cultural and culinary desert. At least that is the sentiment I got used to expressing whenever the subject of the area I settled in was brought up in the context of food, pubs, social life, entertainment. There are no good restaurants, no decent pubs within miles of my humble abode.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-honey-pot-harvester-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-honey-pot-harvester-in-basildon/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Honey Pot Harvester in Basildon Date: June 19, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
This week we had a place called The Owl and Pussycat in our schedule, but a quick look at Google reviews suggested it’s a town bar similar to the Plough and Tractor, i.e. lager and sports on TV, but no food. Perhaps some other time then; for lunch we went to the Honey Pot Harvester instead.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-kings-head-in-billericay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-kings-head-in-billericay/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The King&amp;rsquo;s Head in Billericay Date: October 2, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
When I set off on this pub quest, I wanted to treat it as an anthropological endeavour. We would go, without prejudice, to all the posh gastropubs as well as the neighbourhood boozers, experience the vibe, appreciate the cultural baggage of the landlords, the patrons, the decor, the drink, the food.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-moon-on-the-square-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-moon-on-the-square-in-basildon/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Moon On The Square in Basildon Date: June 6, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
Ah, Weatherspoons! I used to swear by them. The ales for under two pounds a pint – and good too! The gourmet burgers, the curries, all cheap and cheerful. Sure, they’ve lost some of the appeal with this whole brexit thing. The good-old-times interiors seem less welcoming than five years ago, magazines spew out pro-brexit propaganda and today we could even hear a guest asking the waitress in an unfriendly manner “You don’t speak English!</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-noak-bridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-noak-bridge/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Noak Bridge Date: May 14, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
This week it was meant to be The Plough and Tractor in Basildon. Set in a slightly deprived part of town, surrounded by terraced houses and blocks of council flats the pub does not exude character. There is a food truck parked next to the entrance, suggesting that getting lunch inside might be problematic.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-old-doge-inn-in-herongate-tye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-old-doge-inn-in-herongate-tye/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Old Doge Inn in Herongate Tye Date: June 12, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
The Olde Dog Inn was a pleasant break from our recent exploration of chain pubs in the town centre. Located in a tiny village of Herongate Tye, The Dog has all the trappings of a country pub, with low ceilings, crooked walls, Tudor beams, a number of small rooms with tables, and a decent selection of beer.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-quays-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-quays-in-basildon/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Quays in Basildon Date: August 20, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
We arrive in Festival Leisure Park and struggle to pass through to the opposite end, to today’s venue. One road is blocked by a delivery truck, another has lots of cars parked alongside it, despite almost empty car parks next to Premier Inn, Holiday Inn and Travelodge. We eventually manage to get to the corner of the Park by A127, where, nestled between Premier Inn, lake with wakeboarding ramps and cables, skips and temporary fencing is the lunch haunt for today: The Quays.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-robin-in-brentwood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/sw-essex-pub-quest_-the-robin-in-brentwood/</guid><description>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Robin in Brentwood Date: May 18, 2019 Tags: Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review
This wasn’t planned, as we’ve already done our pub quest round this week, but we ended up in Brentwood and Z was hungry, so we popped into The Robin. Located in the North of the town, not far from A12, by a main street, this was an interesting change from chains to a local.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tydzie%C5%84-przed-kilimand%C5%BCaro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/tydzie%C5%84-przed-kilimand%C5%BCaro/</guid><description>Tydzień przed Kilimandżaro Date: January 10, 2016 Tags: Africa, Equipment, Health, Mountains, Preparation, Tanzania
Pozostał nam tydzień do wyjazdu do Tanzanii. Najwyższa pora rozpocząć pakowanie – ale najpierw krótki przegląd kwestii medycznych, bowiem okazało się, że moje notatki sprzed wyprawy azjatycko-australijskiej do czegoś się w końcu przydały. Oszczędziły one nam trochę researchu, ale też tu i ówdzię sprowadziły nas na manowce.
Zdrowie Przy okazji poprzedniego wypadu w tropikalne rejony dwiema podstawowymi kwestiami zdrowotnymi były szczepionki i ochrona przed malarią.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/w-sawannie-i-w-buszu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/w-sawannie-i-w-buszu/</guid><description>W sawannie i w buszu Date: February 7, 2016 Tags: Africa, Food, Luxury, National Park, Safari, Tanzania, Wildlife
Safari polega na tym, że się je, je i je, aż się nie można ruszyć, a później wsiada się w Land Cruisera albo (znacznie rzadziej) w Defendera i jest się wożonym po niesamowitych wertepach. Poza tym ogląda się dzikie zwierzęta – pomimo moich obaw, czy w porze deszczowej jakieś w ogóle można zobaczyć, było ich mnóstwo.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/weso%C5%82a-rozpierducha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/weso%C5%82a-rozpierducha/</guid><description>Wesoła rozpierducha Date: November 15, 2015 Tags: Africa, Cabo Verde, Canary Islands, Cruise, Sailing, Sea
Prolog Statek stoi. Rozpierducha jest totalna, bosman z kapitanem czekają na Jose który umie zrobić, żeby lodówka działała na morzu, a nie tylko w porcie, bo bez tego nie da się płynąć na Karaiby. Jest sobota, Jose ma przyjść we wtorek. Spierdolił się ekran od sondy i wiatromierza, to może naprawić Juan który przyjdzie w poniedziałek.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wizja-lokalna_-cairngorms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wizja-lokalna_-cairngorms/</guid><description>Wizja lokalna: Cairngorms Date: January 28, 2018 Tags: Mountains, Scotland, Walk, Winter
Minęły już dwa lata od Kilimandżaro, nawyższy więc czas znów się trochę sponiewierać. Naczytawszy się Cherry-Garrarda i Shackletona wymyśliłem zimową ekspedycję. Na Grenlandię, czy nawet Svalbard, drogo, i niebezpiecznie – niedźwiedzie polarne, daleko od cywilizacji. Możnaby więc wybrać się gdzieś na północ UK, gdzie leży śnieg – do Cairngorms, na przykład – i powyobrażać sobie, że się jest polarnym podróżnikiem.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wywiad-z-rewolucjonist%C4%85/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mmakowski.github.io/blog/travel/wywiad-z-rewolucjonist%C4%85/</guid><description>Wywiad z rewolucjonistą Date: May 18, 2018 Tags: Bike, England
Nazwa: Dulux Trade London Revolution
Co? Charytatywny rajd rowerowy dookoła Londynu: 300 km w dwa dni.
Limit czasu: około 12 godzin na każdy z dwóch odcinków.
Przesłanki: kiedyś, chyba ze trzynaście lat temu, przejechałem na rowerze trochę ponad 200 km w trzy dni, i było fajnie.
Przygotowanie: pętla przez Upminster i Brentwood, około 50 km w 4 godziny; wycieczka do Bradwell on Sea, około 110 km w 11 godzin; wycieczka do Sevenoaks, około 120 km w 11 godzin.</description></item></channel></rss>