<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chicken on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/chicken/</link><description>Recent content in chicken on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Flooded Queensland Penne</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</guid><description>January 2011 found us in eastern Australia, desperately trying to get to from Cairns to Sydney in time for our flight back home. Despite having a few weeks at our disposal, us reaching Sydney on time was far from certain, due to epic floods that affected much of coastal Queensland. So, we drove around trying to find a passable way South, coming across what looked like deserted towns, with empty shelves at grocery stores and rationed bread, as supplies could not be delivered due to flooded roads.</description></item><item><title>Pig's Legs in Aspic</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</guid><description>I am a fussy eater. When at primary school, I refused to partake of the simple and filling lunches we were served at the canteen, and when asked by a concerned lunch lady what the hell I am eating at home reportedly responded with veal fillet and fries. That was in soviet-era Poland, mind you, where meat was rationed, citizens were prepared to queue for hours to get hold of a frozen carcass of starved and abused chicken and brawls were commonly breaking out over who gets the right to buy the last paper-filled frankfurter.</description></item><item><title>Tesco Finest Salad</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</guid><description>After moving to London to live on my own, I rented a one bed flat located on the top floor of a 16-story high tower block. It was a 1970s, local authority building, and the unquestionable advantages of awesome view over the city, proximity to work and affordability were somewhat counterbalanced by extreme heat in the summer, biting cold in the winter and the council tenants taking their bull terriers to relieve themselves in the lift.</description></item><item><title>Pollo con Pancetta alla Avanzi</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pollo-con-pancetta-alla-avanzi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pollo-con-pancetta-alla-avanzi/</guid><description>For quite a while I have been relying on recipes scavenged from various corners of the web, with little added creativity. There are some which I would like to share my take on, like Jamie’s fish linguine – I even have a nice photo taken already – but going for something so much borrowed would require considerable literary embellishment, which recently I have felt incapable of.
So, Jamie’s fish will have to wait; meanwhile, leftovers to the rescue of creative spirit!</description></item></channel></rss>