<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>privacy on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in privacy on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Hygiene Part 3: Alternative to Google</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-3-alternative-to-google/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-3-alternative-to-google/</guid><description>I vaguely remember Internet search before Google. There was AltaVista and perhaps some other contenders, like Inktomi, Lycos or Excite. Google blew them all out of the water in early 2000s, thanks to minimalistic, user-friendly and search-focused home page and relevant results, not polluted by “sponsored entries”. Over the next decade this evolved into effective monopoly of Internet search, efforts from heavyweight competitors (Microsoft Bing) notwithstanding. Meanwhile, Google spread into multitude of other services whose competitive edge relied on vast amount of knowledge about our habits, interests and values, accumulated as a result of us using those services and giving the data away in return.</description></item><item><title>Digital Hygiene Part 1: VPN</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-1-vpn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/technology/digital-hygiene-part-1-vpn/</guid><description>A few years ago I used to not care much about the digital trail I left all over the internet. The optimistic assumption “nothing to hide, nothing to fear”, convenience of numerous new services that offered some minor perk in exchange for my data, and the general trend for the population of developed world to share more and more, all pushed in that direction. Since then, a couple of developments changed my attitude.</description></item></channel></rss>