<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/beer-england-essex-food-pub-review/</link><description>Recent content in Beer, England, Essex, Food, Pub, Review on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/beer-england-essex-food-pub-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Dog and Partridge in Orsett</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-dog-and-partridge-in-orsett/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-dog-and-partridge-in-orsett/</guid><description>Last Sunday I visited The Four Seasons again, to watch the England vs. Cameroon world cup game. There were some pleasant and unpleasant surprises. The pleasant one was that the ales on tap have changed, and they now had Yardbird pale ale, from Greene King, but pretty decent. The bad was that even though the game was shown on the TV screens around the bar, the sound was off and noone paid any attention.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Noak Bridge</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-noak-bridge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-noak-bridge/</guid><description>This week it was meant to be The Plough and Tractor in Basildon. Set in a slightly deprived part of town, surrounded by terraced houses and blocks of council flats the pub does not exude character. There is a food truck parked next to the entrance, suggesting that getting lunch inside might be problematic. Indeed, the nice barmaid says they don’t serve food, but we can get something from a nearby chippy and have it here, over a drink.</description></item></channel></rss>