<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>england on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/england/</link><description>Recent content in england on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Bell in Horndon on the Hill</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-bell-in-horndon-on-the-hill/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-bell-in-horndon-on-the-hill/</guid><description>For many years my mental map of SW Essex contained just two good dining places: Magic Mushroom and The Bell. It still does, though I have not visited Magic Mushroom for a long time. The Bell used to be the place to take foreign visitors to, to show them a historic English pub and impress with fancy food. The downside: dinners had to be booked a week in advance. Lunches were usually walk-in though.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The King's Head in Billericay</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-kings-head-in-billericay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-kings-head-in-billericay/</guid><description>When I set off on this pub quest, I wanted to treat it as an anthropological endeavour. We would go, without prejudice, to all the posh gastropubs as well as the neighbourhood boozers, experience the vibe, appreciate the cultural baggage of the landlords, the patrons, the decor, the drink, the food. In reality though, we found, sometimes we just don’t have the patience, the curiosity, the inner strength to endure the smell of beer-stained and rarely cleaned carpets, the pastry soggy from gravy, the Greene King IPA.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Quays in Basildon</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-quays-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-quays-in-basildon/</guid><description>We arrive in Festival Leisure Park and struggle to pass through to the opposite end, to today’s venue. One road is blocked by a delivery truck, another has lots of cars parked alongside it, despite almost empty car parks next to Premier Inn, Holiday Inn and Travelodge. We eventually manage to get to the corner of the Park by A127, where, nestled between Premier Inn, lake with wakeboarding ramps and cables, skips and temporary fencing is the lunch haunt for today: The Quays.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Duke's Head in Little Burstead</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-dukes-head-in-little-burstead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-dukes-head-in-little-burstead/</guid><description>We are approaching Billericay on our quest. Things are getting posh. Pastel-coloured walls, wrought iron fireplaces. Scallops for a starter. A burger for £16. But, let us not forget, this is still south Essex; the music is a bit too loud, the bar focuses on lagers at the expense of ales. I don’t want to suggest this is a rule, but we are charged for a beer we did not order.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Boar's Head in Herongate</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-boars-head-in-herongate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-boars-head-in-herongate/</guid><description>A bonus pub visit this week. On the hottest day of the year so far, we went to Thorndon Country Park. It is a lovely area, where one can walk for hours among ancient woodland, dense rhododendron groves, forest clearings and meadows, or just lie down on a grass and read a book (which we did). There are two entrances and car parks, the northern one, from the Brentwood side, which is where we usually go, and the southern one, by A127.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Honey Pot Harvester in Basildon</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-honey-pot-harvester-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-honey-pot-harvester-in-basildon/</guid><description>This week we had a place called The Owl and Pussycat in our schedule, but a quick look at Google reviews suggested it’s a town bar similar to the Plough and Tractor, i.e. lager and sports on TV, but no food. Perhaps some other time then; for lunch we went to the Honey Pot Harvester instead.
Yes, a Harvester is not really a pub. But then, the criteria I used for the quest are far from precise.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Old Doge Inn in Herongate Tye</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-old-doge-inn-in-herongate-tye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-old-doge-inn-in-herongate-tye/</guid><description>The Olde Dog Inn was a pleasant break from our recent exploration of chain pubs in the town centre. Located in a tiny village of Herongate Tye, The Dog has all the trappings of a country pub, with low ceilings, crooked walls, Tudor beams, a number of small rooms with tables, and a decent selection of beer. If there is one thing that spoils this rustic inn charm, that’s the music; I suppose the 1980s pop hits are appreciated by the clientele though, with all of the guests on this Wednesday lunchtime being in their 50s or 60s.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Moon On The Square in Basildon</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-moon-on-the-square-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-moon-on-the-square-in-basildon/</guid><description>Ah, Weatherspoons! I used to swear by them. The ales for under two pounds a pint – and good too! The gourmet burgers, the curries, all cheap and cheerful. Sure, they’ve lost some of the appeal with this whole brexit thing. The good-old-times interiors seem less welcoming than five years ago, magazines spew out pro-brexit propaganda and today we could even hear a guest asking the waitress in an unfriendly manner “You don’t speak English!</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Beehive in Basildon</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-beehive-in-basildon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-beehive-in-basildon/</guid><description>It occurred to me that my long-held belief about lack of pubs in South-West Essex stemmed from a peculiar understanding of what a pub is. What I had in mind was a place that is local and quaint, has unique character and is a bit out of the beaten track. None of the pubs we visited so far had this feel, vindicating in some sense my earlier conviction. Today’s feature, The Beehive in central Basildon, definitely does not alter this conclusion.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Robin in Brentwood</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-robin-in-brentwood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-robin-in-brentwood/</guid><description>This wasn’t planned, as we’ve already done our pub quest round this week, but we ended up in Brentwood and Z was hungry, so we popped into The Robin. Located in the North of the town, not far from A12, by a main street, this was an interesting change from chains to a local. Inside a small bar, regulars watching a football match, a few tables, most of the free ones were in the vicinity of a particularly noisy group of children.</description></item><item><title>SW Essex Pub Quest: The Four Seasons in Laindon</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-four-seasons-in-laindon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/sw-essex-pub-quest/the-four-seasons-in-laindon/</guid><description>I live in a cultural and culinary desert. At least that is the sentiment I got used to expressing whenever the subject of the area I settled in was brought up in the context of food, pubs, social life, entertainment. There are no good restaurants, no decent pubs within miles of my humble abode. I developed this preconceptions shortly after moving to south-west Essex, and have held it for well over a dozen years.</description></item><item><title>Robale z Wharfedale</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/robale-z-wharfedale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/robale-z-wharfedale/</guid><description>W Yorkshire Dales byliśmy po raz pierwszy. Obawiałem się, że na północy Anglii pogoda może nie dopisać, ale weekend wielkanocny był słoneczny i bardzo ciepły również tam; do tego stopnia, że Z się przegrzewała, i musieliśmy robić dłuższe postoje w cieniu.
Pętla z Kettlewell Mieszkaliśmy w Kettlewell. Myślałem, żeby w sobotę rano wstać wcześnie, pojechać do Ribblesdale, zaparkować gdzieś i z tamtąd zrobić pętlę przez największą górę regionu, Pen-y-ghent, ale szczęśliwie poszedłem po rozum do głowy i zdecydowałem jednak przejść się po Wharfedale.</description></item><item><title>Wywiad z rewolucjonistą</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/wywiad-z-rewolucjonist%C4%85/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/wywiad-z-rewolucjonist%C4%85/</guid><description>Nazwa: Dulux Trade London Revolution
Co? Charytatywny rajd rowerowy dookoła Londynu: 300 km w dwa dni.
Limit czasu: około 12 godzin na każdy z dwóch odcinków.
Przesłanki: kiedyś, chyba ze trzynaście lat temu, przejechałem na rowerze trochę ponad 200 km w trzy dni, i było fajnie.
Przygotowanie: pętla przez Upminster i Brentwood, około 50 km w 4 godziny; wycieczka do Bradwell on Sea, około 110 km w 11 godzin; wycieczka do Sevenoaks, około 120 km w 11 godzin.</description></item><item><title>Przyroda i arystokracja</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/przyroda-i-arystokracja/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/przyroda-i-arystokracja/</guid><description>W zeszłym roku Z. wpadła na pomysł, żeby kupić samochód i robić sobie długoweekendowe wypady do parków narodowych. No więc kupiłem, trzynastoletniego Forda StreetKa, któremu po pięciu minutach jazdy wystrzeliła uszczelka z pod głowicy, tak że później bałem się nim jechać dalej niż 10 mil, i ostatecznie sprzedałem go dwóm Rumunom za 300 funtów. Do parków tym niemniej jeździmy, wynajętymi autami, co ma same prawie zalety: wychodzi taniej, samochody są nowiutkie, i można sobie zrobić testy jak się z różnymi autami żyje.</description></item><item><title>Powrót do Dartmoor</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/powr%C3%B3t-do-dartmoor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/powr%C3%B3t-do-dartmoor/</guid><description>Po jedenastu latach wróciliśmy do Dartmoor. Patrząc na zdjęcia, niewiele się zmieniło: te same trzęsawiska, karłowate, omszałe drzewa, kamienne pozostałości z epoki brązu, ciężkie chmury. Wiatr. Przed jedenastu laty nosiłem bandanę zasłaniającą ucho, w które wiało; teraz chodzę w czapce i nieprzewiewnych bluzach. Zmieniliśmy się my: jesteśmy, mówiąc oględnie, bardziej dojrzali. Zamiast wielkich plecaków z karimatami i namiotem mamy samochód – wynajęty, bo nasz, świeżo po wymianie silnika, był zbyt niepewnym środkiem lokomocji na pięćsetkilometrową podróż.</description></item><item><title>Hello Katie</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/hello-katie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/hello-katie/</guid><description>Wyjechaliśmy znów na Wielkanoc do parku narodowego. Poprzednio, wiele już lat temu, wybraliśmy się do Peak District. Mieszkaliśmy na campingu w naszym maleńkim namiocie. Ania przed wyjazdem zrobiła mazurki, podzieliliśmy się nimi z obozującymi obok wspinaczami z Machesteru. W zamian uraczeni zostaliśmy winem z kartonu oraz piosenkami z mp3 na temat zwyczajów mieszkańców Yorkshire. Bardzo był to fajny wyjazd, zrobiliśmy wtedy długi trek wzdłuż Stanage Edge, wyszliśmy wcześnie rano, wróciliśmy po zmroku, bardzo zmęczeni.</description></item><item><title>Glosariusz z północnych rubieży</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/glosariusz-z-p%C3%B3%C5%82nocnych-rubie%C5%BCy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/travel/glosariusz-z-p%C3%B3%C5%82nocnych-rubie%C5%BCy/</guid><description>Wróciłem właśnie z Northumberland, na pograniczu angielsko-szkockim, i jestem strasznie zmachany. Szedłem przez dwa dni lasami, mokradłami i pagórkami, nigdzie żywej duszy, bolały mnie nogi od chodzenia, ramiona i biodra od noszenia plecaka, dieta marchewkowo-bananowo-suszonokiełbasiana wychodziła mi bokiem, rano albo siąpiła mżawka, albo było zimno i nie chciało się wychylać nosa ze śpiwora, chyba się przeziębiłem, a zupełnym już skandalem jest to, że przypiekło mnie słońce, choć ani na chwilę nie wyszło zza grubej warstwy chmur.</description></item></channel></rss>