<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>salad on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/salad/</link><description>Recent content in salad on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/salad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arabba Fennel salad, cold or hot</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</guid><description>A skiing week in a rented apartment usually means serious culinary constraints. So, we have picked the location that is close to the slopes, so that we do not have to take a bus, or walk for 20 minutes in ski boots, and that is not going to break the bank – but other considerations, such as well-equipped kitchen or proximity to the shops inevitably were of secondary importance. We could eat in the resturant, sure, but if we could afford the extortionate prices the resort eateries charge, then presumably we could have stayed in a proper hotel instead of a holiday apartment?</description></item><item><title>What do you do with celeriac</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</guid><description>Having decided to live apart from civilisation, on the outskirts of a tiny hamlet, two hundred thousand souls, I am at the mercy of my local Tesco as far as food supplies are concerned. Some years ago they decided to stop carrying avocados for a few months. Imagine that! You city folks do not understand what real hardship is. Now there is no celeriac. Last autumn celeriac was in constant supply, but somehow it has fallen out of favour this year.</description></item><item><title>Ketosis No. 2</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</guid><description>Have you heard of ketosis? No? Apparently it’s the best thing since the sliced bread, only even better, because there is no bread, so no need to slice anything. There is no bread, because ketosis is all about getting your energy from fat. Apparently a chap has done it for a year, lost weight, has better cholesterol and some other metrics, feels great. Right, count me in. But, the scientific way to do it is being very exact with amounts of all the food ingredients, and really struggling to find foodstuffs which are fatty enough.</description></item><item><title>Tesco Finest Salad</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/tesco-finest-salad/</guid><description>After moving to London to live on my own, I rented a one bed flat located on the top floor of a 16-story high tower block. It was a 1970s, local authority building, and the unquestionable advantages of awesome view over the city, proximity to work and affordability were somewhat counterbalanced by extreme heat in the summer, biting cold in the winter and the council tenants taking their bull terriers to relieve themselves in the lift.</description></item></channel></rss>