<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pasta on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/pasta/</link><description>Recent content in pasta on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/pasta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Flooded Queensland Penne</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/cooking/flooded-queensland-penne/</guid><description>January 2011 found us in eastern Australia, desperately trying to get to from Cairns to Sydney in time for our flight back home. Despite having a few weeks at our disposal, us reaching Sydney on time was far from certain, due to epic floods that affected much of coastal Queensland. So, we drove around trying to find a passable way South, coming across what looked like deserted towns, with empty shelves at grocery stores and rationed bread, as supplies could not be delivered due to flooded roads.</description></item><item><title>Jamie's Fish</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/cooking/jamies-fish/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/cooking/jamies-fish/</guid><description>There are recipes that I gleaned from the Internet, and which I am very fond of. It would be presumptious and unfair to the fine people who first published them online to plagiarise their efforts on this humble blog. But then, if I had prepared a certain dish dozens of times, if I made custom adjustments and modifications, if the sequence of activities is so ingrained in my synapses that preparing it is like driving a car or putting my shoes on – then perhaps it is fair game, after all?</description></item></channel></rss>