<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vegetarian on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/vegetarian/</link><description>Recent content in vegetarian on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/vegetarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Pound Soup</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/one-pound-soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/one-pound-soup/</guid><description>I took my first steps towards independent, adult living one summer in the middle of my university course. I stayed for two months in a shared apartment in central London. It was a summer internship, well paid, but not being used to a regular income, freaked out by the prices of everything in London being a few times higher than in Warsaw, I tried to live on a very tight budget of £50 a week – that included food and tube tickets.</description></item><item><title>Pink Soup</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</guid><description>From my childhood I remember that to maintain the staple lunch of a soup and a main course through the summer heatwaves, the soup had to be replaced with a cold, often milk-based concoction. It is a peculiarly eastern European thing. From Balkans to the Baltic, from tarator to cold borscht, you will find a multitude of summer recipes for a cold soup. Somehow, the westerners often find the idea repulsive.</description></item><item><title>Arabba Fennel salad, cold or hot</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/arabba-fennel-salad-cold-or-hot/</guid><description>A skiing week in a rented apartment usually means serious culinary constraints. So, we have picked the location that is close to the slopes, so that we do not have to take a bus, or walk for 20 minutes in ski boots, and that is not going to break the bank – but other considerations, such as well-equipped kitchen or proximity to the shops inevitably were of secondary importance. We could eat in the resturant, sure, but if we could afford the extortionate prices the resort eateries charge, then presumably we could have stayed in a proper hotel instead of a holiday apartment?</description></item><item><title>What do you do with celeriac</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/what-do-you-do-with-celeriac/</guid><description>Having decided to live apart from civilisation, on the outskirts of a tiny hamlet, two hundred thousand souls, I am at the mercy of my local Tesco as far as food supplies are concerned. Some years ago they decided to stop carrying avocados for a few months. Imagine that! You city folks do not understand what real hardship is. Now there is no celeriac. Last autumn celeriac was in constant supply, but somehow it has fallen out of favour this year.</description></item><item><title>Ketosis No. 2</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/ketosis-no.-2/</guid><description>Have you heard of ketosis? No? Apparently it’s the best thing since the sliced bread, only even better, because there is no bread, so no need to slice anything. There is no bread, because ketosis is all about getting your energy from fat. Apparently a chap has done it for a year, lost weight, has better cholesterol and some other metrics, feels great. Right, count me in. But, the scientific way to do it is being very exact with amounts of all the food ingredients, and really struggling to find foodstuffs which are fatty enough.</description></item><item><title>Sailor Fodder</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sailor-fodder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sailor-fodder/</guid><description>Picture this: you try to bring a massive pot of water to boil to cook some rice. The meal was supposed to be served 15 minutes ago, and the water still refuses to boil. Suddenly, the floor lurches from underneath your feet, you are violently thrown against the cooker and only a small miracle saves you from third-degree burns. Eventually, you manage to put some rice into the water, and after another half an hour there is some hope it might have softened a little.</description></item><item><title>Sans Marigold</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sans-marigold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/sans-marigold/</guid><description>I like travelling a lot – that is, I like it a lot to travel, rather than travelling a lot is what I like – getting to know different cultures, cuisines, all that stuff. Those of you who understand Polish, or are willing to suffer automated translation, can read more about my travel exploits on another blog. This year I have been to Greece and Georgia, and if there is anything common between those two escapades, it is that in those lands of highly regarded cuisine I ended up enjoying salads the most.</description></item><item><title>A Proper Fruit Salad</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/a-proper-fruit-salad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/a-proper-fruit-salad/</guid><description>Fruit salads do not enjoy a good reputation, and perhaps deservedly so. At supermarkets and sandwich joints, what passes as a “fruit salad” is usually nothing more than some random pieces of fruit approaching use-by date diced and sealed in a plastic container. At restaurants, dietetic martyrs who with sad resignation skim through the dessert menu and then announce they will have a fruit salad, attract sympathetic looks and knowing nods.</description></item><item><title>Roasted Root Vegetables</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/roasted-root-vegetables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/roasted-root-vegetables/</guid><description>Commonly when preparing the main course we start with the choice of meat (if any) and the way to cook it, and then treat the vegetables, rice etc. as an addition. For today’s course I’m doing something opposite: make vegetables the cetrepiece, with meat acting as a side dish. The first time I ate something similar was in December 2009 in Lapland, with -30°C outside, so somehow naturally I associate it with winter.</description></item></channel></rss>