<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming languages on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/programming-languages/</link><description>Recent content in programming languages on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mmakowski.com/tags/programming-languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Lambda Calculus</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/technology/introduction-to-lambda-calculus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/technology/introduction-to-lambda-calculus/</guid><description>Software is pervasive in the modern world and has influence over many aspects of our lives. In some cases, such as avionics or medical equipment control, human life depends on the correctness of software. Yet, high profile cases of bugs do not inspire confidence in the state of software engineering.
The “software crisis” is a phenomenon recognised by practitioners of the field. Several ways of addressing the reliability issue have been proposed: from reliance on programmer’s discipline, through tools that perform post-hoc validation of programs to ensure they do not contain suspicious coding patterns, to languages that restrict valid programs to ones whose properties can be formally proven.</description></item><item><title>Five Languages</title><link>https://blog.mmakowski.com/technology/five-languages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mmakowski.com/technology/five-languages/</guid><description>Pick three to five programming languages for teaching orthogonal programming paradigms. Which did you choose? Why? Blog and I&amp;#39;ll share.
&amp;mdash; Rosetta Code (@rosettacode) January 12, 2013 Interesting you should ask that, Rosetta Code. I’ve been pondering similar questions before, most recently inspired by Bruce Tate’s Seven Languages in Seven Weeks, whose languages of choice were sometimes overlapping (e.g. Io and Ruby) while leaving certain areas, such as concatenative languages, unexplored.</description></item></channel></rss>