<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>polish on Maciek's blog</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/polish/</link><description>Recent content in polish on Maciek's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/tags/polish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pink Soup</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pink-soup/</guid><description>From my childhood I remember that to maintain the staple lunch of a soup and a main course through the summer heatwaves, the soup had to be replaced with a cold, often milk-based concoction. It is a peculiarly eastern European thing. From Balkans to the Baltic, from tarator to cold borscht, you will find a multitude of summer recipes for a cold soup. Somehow, the westerners often find the idea repulsive.</description></item><item><title>The Loin of Patience</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-loin-of-patience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/the-loin-of-patience/</guid><description>When I was younger I could not understand the social imperative to treat people older than oneself – in particular the elderly – with esteem. In what way does having lived through a number of decades entitle one to more respect than is shown to a similarly worthy youth? With time I started to appreciate the worth of experience and accept that there are qualities that come with age. One such quality that is stereotypically associated with the elderly and denied the young is patience.</description></item><item><title>Pig's Legs in Aspic</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/pigs-legs-in-aspic/</guid><description>I am a fussy eater. When at primary school, I refused to partake of the simple and filling lunches we were served at the canteen, and when asked by a concerned lunch lady what the hell I am eating at home reportedly responded with veal fillet and fries. That was in soviet-era Poland, mind you, where meat was rationed, citizens were prepared to queue for hours to get hold of a frozen carcass of starved and abused chicken and brawls were commonly breaking out over who gets the right to buy the last paper-filled frankfurter.</description></item><item><title>Wild Boar Fillet à la Białowieża</title><link>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/wild-boar-fillet-%C3%A0-la-bia%C5%82owie%C5%BCa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mmakowski.github.io/blog/cooking/wild-boar-fillet-%C3%A0-la-bia%C5%82owie%C5%BCa/</guid><description>There is often that one ingredient. You’re in a supermarket and a vegetable you don’t normally eat catches your eye, or it’s a jar of some obscure substance that suddenly seems like a promising kernel around which you can build a dinner. Or, it’s something rare, that you got from someone and sits in your pantry waiting for that moment of inspiration. This evening’s dish is going to be of this kind.</description></item></channel></rss>